Hey, sexy.
嘿，美女
I love that dress.
我喜欢那裙子
Of course you do, Lorenzo. You made it.
当然啦，洛伦佐。这就是你做的
- Hi, sweetie. - Hey, guys.
- 嗨，甜心 - 你们好
- There you are. - Lena.
- 你在那儿啊 - 莉娜
- You've done it again. - Well, it's all for you, Bradlee.
- 你又干成了 - 哦，都是为了你啊，布拉德利
Gotta mingle.
该过去玩玩了
Oh, the girls are by the pool.
哦，姑娘们在水池边
Well, well, well, Lena. So where's this sexy boy toy of yours hiding?
哎呀，哎呀，哎呀，莉娜，你的小情郎躲哪儿去了？
I didn't know you were a football fan, Patrick.
我不知道你是橄榄球迷，帕特力克
I've never watched a game. I'm just a big fan of his old underwear ads.
我从不看比赛，我只是特别爱他的老内衣广告
Well, he's probably just getting out of the shower. Let me go hurry his ass up.
他大概刚冲完澡，我这就去揪他出来
- Hi. - Hey, babe.
- 嗨 - 嘿，宝贝
Start of the fourth quarter, and Owens will throw. He's got Brown wide open!
第四节开始，欧文斯要掷球了，他给了大空档里的布朗！
You have got to be kidding me.
你肯定是在逗我玩
Honey, just let me finish the game, I'll take you to the movies.
亲爱的，让我看完这场比赛吧，我会带你去看电影的
Take me to the movies?
带我去看电影？
Hello! There's a huge party going on downstairs.
拜托！楼下正在大聚会
Remember the catering trucks and the valet parkers?
还记得餐车和停车服务员吗？
Oh, shit, I forgot.
哦，该死，我忘记了
I'll tell you what you should forget about.
我来告诉你该忘记什么
Football.
橄榄球
Because it's forgotten all about you.
因为有了它你就会什么都忘掉
Now, you're going to put this outfit on that I bought you,
现在，你这醉鬼
drag your drunken ass downstairs
快穿上我给你买的衣服到楼下去
and mingle with my clients like a good boy.
像好孩子一样陪陪我的客人
Who am l? Elton John? I ain't wearing that shit.
我是谁？埃尔顿・约翰吗？我才不穿这鬼玩意呢
- Yes, you are. - I'm not your trained monkey, honey.
- 你要穿的 - 我可不是你训练的猴子，亲爱的
No. You're much more expensive than that.
对啊，你比猴子可贵多了
But I tell you what.
不过听我说
If you're not downstairs in five minutes,
要是五分钟以后你还没下楼
I'm gonna throw you out of my bed,
我就要让你滚下我的床
out of my house and out of my life.
滚出我的家，滚出我的生活
Then you're gonna have to pay for your own bananas.
然后你就得自个儿买香蕉吃了
I'm just so mad at you because you're not wearing my gift.
我生气是因为你没穿我的礼物
Gift?
礼物？
What gift?
什么礼物？
It's like a l-love-you gift. I left it in the closet for you.
给爱人的礼物咯，我把它放在壁橱里了
Really?
真的？
Paul, I'm so excited.
保罗，我太激动了
I can't believe you did this.
想不到你会给我送礼
- Where'd you put it? - In the back, on the right.
- 你放在哪儿了？ - 在后面，右边
Paul? Paul, what are you doing?
保罗？保罗，你干什么？
I think we need some alone time, honey,
我看咱们都需要单独待会儿
so I'm gonna go take a cruise in your Bentley.
所以我打算开你那辆本特利去兜兜风
Don't you dare take my car, you drunken bastard!
混蛋醉鬼，你敢开我的车？
- I own you! - I love you.
- 你是我的人！ - 我是爱你的人
Somebody please open this damn door! Patrick?
来人啊，把这该死的门开开！帕特力克？
- Lena? - Patrick.
- 莉娜？ - 帕特力克
What happened to you?
你出什么事了？
He locked me in the closet and left me to die.
他把我锁在壁橱里就不管了
Oh, my God, he is deranged!
上帝啊，他疯了！
He thinks he can mess with me.
他以为他可以捉弄我
Oh, man. Here come the party poopers.
哦，捣乱的家伙来了
Well, well, well. I'll be damned. If it isn't Paul Crewe.
哎呀，哎呀，哎呀，假如这不是保罗・克鲁，那我就是见鬼了
So, what did I do wrong? Was I driving poorly?
我做错什么了？我是不是违章驾驶了？
Nope. Nope. This car was reported stolen.
没有，没有，有人报告说这车被偷了
No, no, no. It's actually my girlfriend's car.
不，不，不，其实这是我女朋友的车
Shit happens.
真见鬼
Shit does happen. I mean, look what happened to your ears.
是见鬼了，我是说，瞧瞧你那耳朵
I gotta ask you something. Does he get XM Radio with those?
我得问问你，他就用那耳朵听XM Radio？ （一家卫星广播公司）
Actually, they get a couple of channels.
确实能听到几个频道
It's Paul Crewe.
这是保罗・克鲁
Another question, though.
那么还有一个问题
Santa Claus. What's he like?
圣诞老人。他长什么样？
Boy, I hate to arrest a public figure like yourself,
小伙子，我不想逮捕你这样的名人
but, hell, I don't think you got too many
不过我想，你现在
endorsement deals to worry about, now, do you?
没有太多公事要办吧？对吗？
Now, listen here, Mr. Frodo. Don't get short with me.
听着，弗罗多先生，别小看我
That was good. I mean, he's good.
很棒，我是说，他很棒
Man. I hope you got a lot of money for that game you threw,
老兄，希望你有很多钱来玩这场游戏
because that was the most pathetic thing I ever saw.
因为这是我见过的最惨的事了
Now, step out of the vehicle, Mr. Crewe.
现在下车吧，克鲁先生
Don't you think I should pull the car over more? I could get sideswiped.
你不觉得我该把车开过去一点吗？可能会被人蹭到的
You're slurring your words a bit there, Paul. You been drinking tonight?
你口齿不太清楚，保罗今晚一直在喝酒？
Absolutely not. Now, could you do me a favor? Hold this beer while I back it up.
绝对没有，帮个忙好吗？拿着这个，我倒一下车
Hey, you can finish that one. I got five more. Take care, guys.
嘿，你就把那罐喝完吧，我还有五罐呢。保重，哥们
We got a 3-94 in progress.
我们正在处理3-94情况
Okay, remain calm.
好的，冷静
How you doing? What's up? What's up? What's up?
你好吗？好吗？好吗？好吗？
What you are watching is live footage of a vehicle, apparently stolen,
现在您看到的是实况直播，警方正在追逐
being pursued by police.
一辆明显是被盗的车辆
We're receiving word now that the driver of that vehicle
我们现在得到消息说，这辆车的司机
is former Pittsburgh football star Paul Crewe.
是匹兹堡的前橄榄球明星保罗・克鲁
Crewe, you might remember,
您可能记得
was the only man ever to be indicted on federal racketeering charges
克鲁是唯一因为在职业橄榄球赛中打假球
for shaving points in a professional football game,
而遭到联邦的诈骗罪起诉的人
although it was never fully proven.
尽管此事从未被完全证实
Yeah!
Yeah！
- Hello. - Do not get one more scratch
- 喂 - 不准再刮伤我的车
on my car, or I will slit your throat.
要不然我就割断你的喉咙
See, that's our problem, sweetie.
你瞧，我们的问题就在这儿
You care about this car more than you do us.
你对这车比对我们俩还要关心
And how'd you even know there was a scratch on this baby?
再说你怎么知道这宝贝已经被刮伤了？
Because I am watching you on TV, as is the whole country.
因为我就在电视上看着你，全国人民都在看
Once again, you are proving to everyone
你又一次向所有人证明
what a worthless piece of shit you are.
你是个一文不值的垃圾
Well, I hope they like this.
啊，但愿他们喜欢这样
Hey, Lena!
嘿，莉娜！
I think we should start seeing other people!
我想可以正式分手了！
I think I'm in love.
我想我是爱上某人了
Good news, boys, I didn't spill my beer.
好消息，小伙子们，我没把啤酒洒出来
Without question, Crewe's five-year federal probation for point-shaving
毫无疑问，今晚克鲁严重违反了
has been severely violated tonight.
五年假球缓刑期中的限制规定
The future of this once-great football star looks very dark indeed.
这位曾红极一时的橄榄球明星，看来前途非常黯淡
Long way from the big city, huh, superstar?
这下远离大城市了吧？大明星？
Staying with the times around here, huh?
在这里过日子吗？
Ain't she beautiful?
她是不是很美？
Home sweet home, boy.
到家了，孩子
Get on your feet.
站起来
You're one lucky son of a bitch, Crewe.
你是个幸运的狗杂种，克鲁
- Is that right? - That's right.
- 是吗？ - 是的
See, the warden loves his football.
典狱长很爱橄榄球
Fact, he was on the winning side of your little thing.
事实上，你那次的比赛，他支持的是赢球一方
- Well, tell him congratulations. - But I wasn't.
- 哦，那要恭喜他了 - 可我没有
Welcome to Allenville.
欢迎来阿伦维尔
Thank you, sergeant. I'll take it from here.
谢谢你，警长，从这里开始就交给我吧
- Afternoon, inmate Crewe. - Yeah.
- 下午好，犯人克鲁 - 啊
Come on. Warden wants to see you.
来吧，典狱长要见你
Let's do it.
咱们走
Move it.
快走
I used to play a little college ball myself.
我自己在大学里也打过一点球
Down at the University of Miami.
在迈阿密大学
I bet a lot of your old teammates are locked up in here.
你肯定有很多老队友给关在这里
No inmates from my playing days. Couple of guards, though.
我的老队友里没有犯人，倒是有几个看守
See, we got us a fine prison-guard league down here.
瞧，我们这里有个很棒的狱警联盟
It's like a company softball team.
就像公司垒球队
Now, the warden...
现在，典狱长...
...he's gonna ask you to help out.
…他想叫你帮个忙
Okay. With what?
好啊，帮什么忙？
That wasn't nice.
那可不好
When the warden asks you,
典狱长问你的时候
what are you gonna say?
你要怎么说？
Yes?
行？
You're gonna tell him "no." You got it?
你要对他说“不”，明白吗？
You're gonna tell the warden
你要对典狱长说
that you want nothing to do with his football fantasies.
你不想和他的橄榄球爱好扯上关系
Not in my back yard.
不想在我的后院里这么干
Because the warden don't run this prison. I do.
因为管这监狱的不是典狱长，是我
You understand?
你明白了？
Not entirely.
没有全明白
Okay. I feel you, dog. I feel you.
好，我明白了，坏蛋，我明白了
Paul "Wrecking" Crewe.
“破坏王”保罗・克鲁
I don't get to say this to my new guests very often,
虽然我不会经常对我的新客人这样说
but it's an honor to have you here at this institution.
不过你能来这里我真是感到荣幸
It's an honor to be locked up here, sir.
被关在这里我也很荣幸，先生
Oh, well, this is Errol Dandridge.
哦，对了，这是埃罗尔・丹德里奇
Colonel Sanders been eating his own chicken.
山德士上校一直在吃自己的鸡肉 （把他比作肯德基老头了）
He's my political adviser.
他是我的政治顾问
See, I've been approached by several very influential people
曾有几个非常有影响的人和我接触过
wondering if I'd be interested in standing for governor.
问我是否有兴趣当州长
They see the way I run this prison, think maybe I should run this state.
因为他们看到了我对这座监狱的管理，觉得我也许能管理整个州
Only with less sodomy, right?
只不过是鸡奸案少一点，对吗？
Hopefully none.
我希望是没有
Sorry.
对不起
Now, there are two things we take very seriously here in the state of Texas.
在德克萨斯州我们对两样东西特别重视
Prison and football.
监狱和橄榄球
We play a little of the latter here.
在这里我们也打一点橄榄球
The warden is too modest to admit that his team is rather good.
典狱长太谦虚了，不肯承认他的球队非常好
But not good enough.
但是好得不够
Five years since our last championship.
上次夺冠是在五年前
Five years.
五年了
Now, I've worked real hard, pulled strings,
我千方百计通路子
called in quite a few favors to get you here, Paul.
托了很多人情才把你搞到这里来，保罗
Now, why would you go and do that?
那么，你愿意干吗？
Because I am convinced that you can get us back on track.
因为我相信你能让我们重回正轨
I haven't played football in I don't know how long. I don't really want to.
我自己都不记得有多久没打橄榄球了，我真的不想干
You wouldn't be playing, Paul. Just consulting.
你不用打比赛，保罗，只要当顾问就行
Anyone who was once the MVP of the National Football League
当选过国家橄榄球联盟MVP的人
must have a great deal of expertise to offer.
肯定能提供很多专家意见
Captain, what would you say to Mr. Crewe looking in,
队长，假如让克鲁先生用他的经验来教导我们
giving us the benefit of his experience?
你有什么意见？
I think that's a real good idea, warden. We can use all the help we can get.
我觉得这是很好的主意，典狱长 可以利用我们能够获得的一切帮助
Well, then, it's all settled.
好，那么就全妥了
What you say, Paul?
你怎么说，保罗？
I appreciate the offer, but I'm gonna have to pass.
我很感谢你的邀请 但是我想放弃
Now, I can assure you
我可以向你保证
that your time here will be a whole lot easier if you just participate.
只要你参加，你在这里的日子就会轻松得多
I just wanna do my time and go home. Nothing else.
我只想自己过完日子然后回家，没别的了
If you'll excuse us, Mr. Crewe.
请你见谅，克鲁先生
Captain Knauer, you can stay.
科纳瓦队长，你留一下
Sit down!
坐下！
I used to love your underwear commercials.
我以前很喜欢你做的内衣广告
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
My ex-husband wore the same brand of tighty whities.
我前夫穿的紧身衣就是那种牌子
He didn't fill them out quite as well as you, though.
不过不像你能把衣服撑得那么满
Special effects. Hollywood. Not all me.
特效，好莱坞的把戏，不全是因为我
Oh, I doubt that very seriously.
哦，我非常怀疑
Well, then get him enthusiastic, damn it!
好，那就让他变得热心，妈的！
Come on, get up.
来吧，起来.
How'd it go in there? We all set now?
怎么样？现在全搞定了？
Oh, yeah, we're real tight.
对啊，我们配合得真好
Only the finest for you, superstar.
只给你最好的，大明星
I was just playing.
开玩笑而已
I ain't gonna forget you, Crewe.
我不会忘记你的，克鲁
Hey, yo, you owe me money on that game, punk!
嘿，你那场比赛害我输了钱，混蛋！
Better watch yourself, Mr. Football!
你最好当心点，橄榄球先生！
Bitch!
婊子！
Yeah, you better run, woman.
对，你最好逃，娘们
Yo, football.
喂，橄榄球
Take a seat.
坐吧
Thanks.
谢谢
You know, I have never seen one inmate just walk in here
知道吗，我还从没见过哪个犯人
and be unanimously hated by the entire population.
一进来就让所有人都恨的
- I ain't never seen it. - How'd I get so lucky?
- 从来没见过 - 我怎么会这么走运？
You could have robbed banks, sold crack,
你可以抢银行、贩毒
stole your grandmama's pension, and nobody would have cared.
偷你奶奶的养老金，没人会在乎
But shaving points off a football game? Man, that's just un-American.
可是在橄榄球赛里打假球？老兄，那可不是美国人干的事
- You play football? - Me? No.
- 你打橄榄球？ - 我？不
I suck so bad, they used to pick me after the white kids.
我太没用，他们以前先挑白人，孩子再挑我
Used to be mad too. It's like, "l can't believe I picked a nigga that can't play."
他们还曾经被我搞到发疯，心想： “真不敢相信，我挑了个不会打球的黑鬼”
- Caretaker. - Paul Crewe.
- 我叫凯尔泰克 - 保罗・克鲁
Whatever your pleasure, I can facilitate.
你想要什么我都能帮忙
You need weed, you need meth-- Hey, you need Prozac, I'm your man.
你想要大麻，想要冰毒-- 或者想要百忧解，找我就对了
I know how you white boys always deal with that depression.
我知道你们白人总是得忧郁症
I mean, me personally, I don't understand what you white boys
我是说，从我个人角度来看
all depressed about. Hey, you're white. Smile.
我不明白你们白人都在忧郁个啥 嘿，你是白人啊，笑一笑
And for a small fee, I can even get you McDonald's.
稍微付点报酬，我连麦当劳快餐都能帮你搞到
- Really? - Yeah, that's right. Mickey D's.
- 真的？ - 对，Mickey D的
My man Cheeseburger Eddy got the hookup.
我兄弟汉堡包埃迪有门路
Cheeseburger Eddy?
汉堡包埃迪？
That's right. We can get our McFlurry on.
没错，可以给你吃麦旋风
Enjoy it, fat man.
吃吧，胖子
What about the love of a beautiful woman?
能搞到漂亮女人的爱情吗？
Well, you're gonna have to lower your standards
哦，那你得降低一下
on the beautiful part and on the woman part.
关于漂亮的标准和关于女人的标准
Hey.
嘿
Let's just stick with the cheeseburgers.
咱们还是只谈汉堡包吧
Oh, they ugly now, but in eight months, he gonna look like Beyoncé.
啊，他们现在是挺丑，但是过了八个月 你就会觉得他像碧昂斯（当红女歌星）
No, thanks.
不，谢了
Now, here's the most important part.
那，现在是最重要的问题
You can't let these guys scare you. You can't let them punk you.
你不能让这些家伙吓住，不能让他们瞧不起你
Because if you do that, you gonna end up being somebody's bitch.
因为要是你那样做了，你最后就会变成别人的婊子
Don't want that. Thanks for the advice.
那我可不要，谢谢你的忠告
Hey. Let me take that tray out for you.
嘿，我帮你把盘子拿走吧
I ain't done eating yet.
我还没吃完呢
Oh, you're not? I'll give it back to you, then.
哦，没吃完？那我还给你
You're dead!
你死定了！
Hornet's Nest!
马蜂窝！
Everybody stay down.
全都趴着别动
Stay quiet!
不许出声！
Come on, Crewe, get up.
来吧，克鲁，起来
Get up, superstar.
起来，大明星
Yes, sir.
是，长官
You think you can do anything you want around here, don't you?
你以为在这儿想干什么就能干什么，是吗？
Well, you are no different than any other piece of shit
哈，你跟管这地方叫“家”的其他垃圾
that calls this place home.
没什么两样
Really? These guys think you're a dumb redneck too?
真的？这些家伙也觉得你是个乡巴佬？
Girl, that's your new boo.
小妞，那是你的新绰号
You better cut that shit out. It's getting old.
最好收回你那一套，已经不新鲜了
That's gonna cost you.
这下你死定了
Looking forward to it.
我盼着呢
Wake up, Sleeping Beauty.
醒一醒，睡美人
Hey, superdick.
嘿，鸟人
Warden's wondering if your stay in the hotbox has changed your mind.
典狱长想知道你在蒸笼里呆过以后是不是改了主意
How long have I been in here?
我在这里多久了？
One week. Wanna go for two?
一个星期。想呆两星期吗？
How'd you find these guys anyways?
话说回来，你是怎么找到这些家伙的？
Recruitment, boy.
招募的，孩子
When college stars don't get drafted, they need a place to go.
大学里的明星要是没进职业队，总得有个地方去
A job, money, security.
有工作，有钱，有社会保险
Who drank all the damn Gatorade?!
谁他妈把佳得乐都喝了？
Damn it!
该死的！
And apparently steroids.
显然还有类固醇
Look, seems like you got all the talent you'd want. So why do you need me?
你看，你好像已经得到了 你想要的所有人才。为什么还需要我？
Well, now, you might find this hard to believe,
啊，你可能觉得难以置信
but there's folks here in the prison league don't care for me very much.
监狱联盟里有些人对我不太喜欢
- You, warden? - They thought it might be amusing
- 你？典狱长？ - 他们觉得在第一场比赛
to schedule the defending league champs as our first game.
就安排我们和联盟冠军打，会很有意思
And me? Well, I thought an old pro like yourself
而我呢？我觉得你这样的职业老手
might have some training-camp tricks, drills, insights to offer up.
也许能提供一些训练的诀窍、高招、秘方
Give us the competitive edge.
让我们有竞争优势
All right. Relatively simple. You need a tune-up game.
好的，这比较简单，你需要一场热身赛
A tune-up game?
热身赛？
Yeah. In college, we'd start every season against Appalachian State
对。在大学里，我们每个赛季开始时 都会跟阿巴拉契亚的队
or some slack Division ll team.
或是什么很烂的二线队打
Kick the living shit out of them. Get their confidence up.
把他们打得屁滚尿流，鼓舞一下队员的自信心
You know something, Paul?
你知道吗，保罗？
- You've just given me an inspiration. - That's great. What?
- 你刚给了我一个灵感 - 太好了。是什么？
You're gonna assemble a team to play the first game against us.
你要组一支队来和我们打第一场比赛
And you, Mr. Crewe, are gonna be the quarterback.
而你，克鲁先生，将是四分卫
I don't think so.
我不同意
Let me tell you something.
听我说
In my prison, to get along, you gotta go along.
在我的监狱里，要想过下去，你就得照办
I just wanna do my three years and be done.
我只想蹲满三年然后走人
Three years is before you assaulted Captain Knauer.
在袭击科纳瓦队长之前，你的刑期是三年
Now, you could be with us for a very long time, Mr. Crewe.
现在，你可能要陪我们很长一段日子了，克鲁先生
Fine, I'll do it.
好吧，我干
Good choice.
正确选择
But one condition, though.
不过有一个条件
Gotta promise me to keep Captain Knauer off my back.
你要答应不让科纳瓦队长暗算我
It's a deal.
那就说定了
Now, you got four weeks to assemble a team and train them.
那么，你有四个星期来组一支队并训练他们
What, are we gonna have a half-hour a day to practice with a Nerf ball?
什么，我们是不是每天只能用软球练半小时？
Oh, I'll make sure my boys allow you sufficient freedom, within these walls,
哦，在这些大墙以内，我保证让我的人给你充分的自由
to get your team in shape.
来使你的球队成型
What's this? "Football 'tree-outs."'
这是什么？“橄榄球先拔？”
What the hell is a "tree-out"?
什么叫“先拔”？
"Tryout," you half a meatball.
“选拔”，你个笨猪
- What's this football thing about, man? - Crewe's getting a team together.
- 这橄榄球是怎么回事，哥们？ - 克鲁正在组一支球队
- To play against who? - The guards.
- 跟谁打？ - 看守
Now, I don't know about y'all, but I occasionally have the impulse
我不知道你们都是怎么想的，不过我有时会有冲动
to physically assault one of our finer correctional officers.
想要揍一揍我们的某位优秀管教人员
Yeah? Well, how the hell we gonna get to do that?
哦？那到底怎么才能做到？
Just show up at the "tree-outs," you big, dumb bitch.
在“先拔”上亮一手就行了，你个大呆瓜
Do the girls get to play?
女孩子也能打球吗？
We're playing footballs, not balls-balls.
我们打的是橄榄球，不是卵球
This is bullshit. Just another chance for the guards to beat on us.
这是放屁。只不过又给看守一个机会来打我们
Don't you idiots get it? We could get a free shot at the guards.
你们这些白痴还不明白？我们可以放开手脚打那些看守
This is our turn. We could beat up on them.
这下轮到我们出手了，我们可以把他们胖揍一顿
We could kill them.
我们可以宰了他们
Kill them.
宰了他们
You know MVP sold his own teammates out.
你们都知道，MVP把自己的队友出卖了
What do you think he's gonna do to you fools?
你们觉得他会对你们这些傻瓜干什么？
And that's the truth. With some cheese on it.
这才是真理，上面还有些奶酪呢
There ain't no meat loaf between these buns.
这两片屁股中间可没肉饼
Yo, man, that's my flier, man! I worked hard on it!
喂，那是我的布告，老兄！费了好大劲做的！
You see? He ran like a little bitch, right? You saw that, right?
看见了？他像个小婊子一样跑了 对吧？你看见了，对吧？
Yo, team needs you. Team needs you.
哦，球队需要你。球队需要你
You sh-- You come to the tr-- Come to the tree-outs.
你-- 你来参加--参加先拔吧
Crappy field, shit-ass equipment...
蹩脚场地，垃圾器材...
Hey, man, at least we got some world-class players over there.
嘿，老兄，至少那边有几个世界级选手
Forty-five.
四十五
Forty-six.
四十六
Forty-seven.
四十七
He might make the team.
他说不定能撑起这支球队
Well, if we gotta cut him, you're doing it.
好啊，假如要把他刷下来，就由你去说
Forty-nine.
四十九
Fifty.
五十
- All right, man. - Good job, man.
- 好，老兄 - 干得好
Well, well, well. You a football player?
好，好，好，你是橄榄球运动员？
Oh, no. I never played no football, mister.
啊，不。从没打过橄榄球，先生
So, what happened? You read the flier, thought it looked like some fun?
那么，是怎么回事？你看了布告，觉得这比较好玩？
- Oh, I can't read. - Oh, don't worry.
- 哦，我不识字 - 哦，没关系
Reading's for rich people.
读书是有钱人的事
So you know, we're putting together a football team. Love you to join.
那么你知道，我们正在组织橄榄球队，欢迎你加入
Will you teach me to football?
你会教我打橄榄球？
Sure we'll teach you to football. Won't we, Caretaker?
我们当然会教你打，对吧，凯尔泰克？
Hey, I'll teach you anything. Just don't eat me.
嘿，我什么都会教你，只要别吃了我就行
Okay.
好啊
Down, Shrek. Down!
放下，史瑞克，放下！ （把他比作怪物史瑞克了）
Okay, bring it in. Whoever's trying out for the team, wake up.
好，来吧。想参加球队选拔的都起来
Can you give a brother a little hustle?
拿出点精神给哥们儿看看好不好？
Very good.
很好
For those of you who don't know who I am, I'm Paul Crewe.
可能有人还不知道我是谁，我是保罗・克鲁
I'm gonna be your coach, your captain, your quarterback.
我将是你们的教练，你们的队长，你们的四分卫
You haven't played in years. Why can't I be quarterback?
你有几年没打球了，为什么不能让我打四分卫？
- You're right. Let's see what you got. - All right.
- 说得对。咱们看看你的本事 - 好啊
- Hit me, I'm open. - Hike, hike! Hike!
- 扔过来，我接着 - 传，传！传！
That's why. Now, sit down and shut up.
这就是为什么，现在坐下，闭上你的嘴
It slipped. I just ate popcorn.
是滑了一下，我刚才吃爆米花来着
Question: Any of you gentlemen ever play football before?
提问：先生们，有谁以前打过橄榄球？
- You did? Where? - Kansas State.
- 你打过？在哪儿？ - 堪萨斯州队
Are you shitting me? For Coach Snyder?
你耍我吧？在施奈德教练手下？
Kansas State Prison.
堪萨斯州立监狱队
Now, I hear they have the softest mattresses out there.
我听说那儿的床垫最软了
Yeah, they do.
没错，是这样
Not as soft as the ones at West Texas Mental lnstitution.
不如西德克萨斯精神病院的软
- Really? - Let's finish this conversation later.
- 真的？ - 有话咱们以后再说吧
For now, I wanna see what you got out there.
现在，我要看看你们的水平
We'll grade them on a scale of one to ten.
从一到十给他们打分
Move it! Hustle, hustle, hustle!
快啊！加油，加油，加油！
Give these guys sixes. Give these guys fives.
给这些人六分，给这些人五分
Good. Good. Give them threes.
好，好，给他们三分
Very nice!
非常好！
- Aren't we missing somebody? - Where's the Kansas State guy?
- 是不是漏了谁？ - 堪萨斯州队的那家伙呢？
You assholes better not cut me! I'm still on this team!
你们这些混蛋最好别把我刷下来！我还在这队里呢！
Negative two.
负二
All right, go with negative two.
好的，就给他负二
Hey! Somebody bring me a Diet Coke!
嘿！来人，给我一瓶节食可乐！
- Let's do this! - That's it!
- 来吧！ - 好的！
Five.
五分
Good. Seven.
好。七分
Stupid tire! You're a fricking tire!
笨蛋轮胎！你这破烂胎！
You think you're better than me?! I'll kick your ass!
你以为你比我强？我要揍扁你！
Three.
三分
And a half?
再加半分？
Yeah. That's better.
行，那比较好
Okay. Good.
好的，很好
Yeah. Hit that bag, man. There you go, man.
对，撞那沙袋，你上，老兄
Four.
四分
- Five. I don't know. - I go.
- 五分。我不知道 - 我上
Come on, Switowski!
上吧，斯韦托斯基！
Daddy!
爸爸！
Oh, man!
哦，厉害！
- Look at that. - He got it off the hinge.
- 瞧瞧 - 他把沙袋从链子上扯下来了
- I think that's a ten. - Let's go with a ten.
- 我看该打十分 - 那就打十分吧
I'm sorry. I "brokeded" your toy.
对不起。我“打破破”了你的玩具
No, that's a good thing. You should have a victory hug with Caretaker.
没关系，那很好，你该和凯尔泰克拥抱一下
What? What you talking about, man? Hey!
什么？你说什么？嘿！
Asshole!
混蛋！
Okay, fellas, it's pretty simple. You do a buttonhook.
好，伙计们，这很简单，你们做一次钮扣钩
The rest of you guys block for me. I'll take care of the rest.
你们其余的人替我阻挡，剩下的我来解决
Okay? On "go." On "go."
好吗？上，上
Ready? Break!
预备？开始！
We'll work on that.
我们慢慢来吧
Okay, half speed on this one, guys. Slow and easy.
好，用一般速度，慢一点，别着急
Ready?!
预备？
Go!
开始！
Stop it!
停下！
Stop the violence!
停止暴力行为！
Can't we all get along?
我们不能和平相处吗？
- Hey, Paul. - Unger.
- 嘿，保罗 - 昂格尔
- Team's looking great. - Oh, yeah.
- 球队看起来很棒 - 哦，是啊
- So are you. - Yep. Working on it.
- 你也是 - 对，正在努力
The blood of the guards is gonna flow like the rivers of ancient Babylon.
看守们会像古代巴比伦那样血流成河
That's good news. Unger, you're the man.
那是好消息，昂格尔，你真好
Good job today. You're all starting to look really sharp out there. Yeah.
今天干得很好。你们开始像个样子了
See you tomorrow.
明天见
- We're gonna suck. - Yeah. No doubt about it.
- 我们会很惨 - 是啊，毫无疑问
You look like you could use a little help.
看来你们需要一点帮助
No offense, my man, but you're a little seasoned.
不是我笑话你，老兄，你看来有点年头了
Seasoned?
有点年头？
I'm not asking to play. I'll coach. I'm Nate Scarborough.
我不是想打球。我想做教练，我是内特・斯卡波罗
Nate Scarborough?
内特・斯卡波罗？
The Heisman Trophy winner from Oklahoma?
是俄克拉荷马的海斯曼奖杯获得者？
The inmate from cellblock D.
是D区牢房的囚犯
But about a hundred years ago, when I could run and gun,
不过，大概在一百年前我还能跑能打的时候
yeah, I was a Sooner then.
我确实是俄克拉荷马州人
I heard you were dead.
我听说你已经死了
No, I ain't dead. I've been right here, rotting.
不，我没死，我一直在这里发臭
Waiting for a chance to get back at those sadistic guards.
等待一个机会，回敬那些虐待狂看守
Waiting. For this.
等着，这个机会
Well, coach, as you can see,
那么，教练，你也看到了
we don't exactly have the cream of the crop to work with here.
这里的精英其实没有和我们合作
Well, what are we gonna do? How are we gonna find players?
那我们该怎么办？怎么才能找到球员？
How'd they get you to go to Florida State?
他们怎么让你进佛罗里达州队的？
They recruited me.
他们把我招进去的
I'll get the strippers.
我去找人来
Well, now, Lindsay, this isn't about credit or congratulations.
哦，林赛，这不是关于赞颂或祝贺的问题
This is about giving men who've made mistakes in their lives
这是关于给失足者一个机会
an opportunity to rise above themselves.
让他们改过自新
To move beyond the bars of containment.
走出铁窗的问题
Say what?
说什么？
What I would do to you.
我要对你做什么
Yeah. Nice boot, skin man.
好，踢得好，小子
Hey, why does he get to be the kicker? I was All-State, man.
嘿，为什么让他踢球？我可是国家级选手
Let's see what you got.
咱们看看你的本事
That's why, you dumb-ass.
这就是为什么，蠢驴
Just go do some laps.
还是去跑圈吧
I heard you boys needed to see me.
我听说你们找我有事
Yeah. I want you to meet Skitchy.
对，我介绍你认识斯基奇
Hey, dog. Check that building over there.
嘿，老兄，到那幢房子里去看看吧
They keep all the records in the basement.
他们把所有记录都放在地下室里
He's been here so long, he knows where everything is.
他在这里呆得太久了，知道每样东西在哪里
That ain't necessarily a good thing, is it?
这可不一定是好事啊，对吗？
I had a parole date in '86. But I got in a tussle with a guard and...
我的假释期在86年，但是我跟看守打了一架，所以...
One punch and it went away.
就一拳，假释就没了
Twenty extra years for one punch?
为了一拳就多关二十年？
Well, unfortunately for him, the guard he punched
他很倒霉，他打的那个看守
just happens to be the warden now.
如今恰好成了典狱长
Oh, shit. Warden Hazen?
哦，该死。海岑典狱长？
"Oh, shit" is right.
“哦，该死”，说得对
Fight in the yard. Send backup.
院子里有人打架，快派人支援
Right on time.
来得正好
- Let's do it.
- 咱们干吧
Ain't you guys glad you got a black man for a friend?
有个黑人做朋友，你们很高兴吧？
- Hell, yeah. - Come on.
- 是啊 - 走吧
Hazen has a rating system for every con.
海岑给每个犯人都评了级
What's three stars?
三星是什么意思？
The more prone to violence that the inmate is, the more stars he gets.
犯人的暴力倾向越重，星数就越多
Five stars is the max.
最高是五星
I didn't know that. Let's see how many stars my maniacal ass got.
我还不知道有这事，瞧瞧我这个疯子得了几颗星
Half a star? That's gotta be a mistake. Check it again. Check it again.
半颗星？这肯定是搞错了，再看看，再看看
You're about as maniacal as a boxful of kittens.
你大概就和一箱子小猫咪一样疯
Come on, that's not funny, man.
什么话？这可不好笑
I'm gonna have to stab somebody or something. Get my rep up.
我该去捅个人，让我的级别涨上去
Why don't we have a maniacal pillow fight tonight. That could get it up some.
那我们今晚就来个疯狂枕头战吧，那可以让你的级别涨一点
Yeah. We can sell it to pay-per-view.
对，我们还可以卖门票
Superstar Versus Half-a-Star.
超级明星对战半颗星
Why don't you shut up before I slit your throat and watch the dust come out.
你给我闭嘴，要不我就割了你的喉咙，看里面的灰尘飘出来
Come on, guys, we only got a couple minutes.
好啦，哥们，我们只有几分钟时间
How about this guy?
这家伙怎样？
Damn, this fool got the chair three times, ain't died yet.
操，这傻瓜上了三次电椅，还没死
Well, we may not have the most talented team,
嗯，我们也许得不到最有才华的球队
but we will definitely have the meanest.
但是肯定有最残忍的球队
- What's he doing that for? - Because he's a freak.
- 他为什么这么干？ - 因为他是个变态
Hey, Sasquatch! Someone's here to see you!
嘿，大脚怪兽！有人来看你了！
Not too smart on your part.
你这样可不太聪明
Hey.
嘿
How's the headbanging coming?
撞脑袋好玩吗？
You're bleeding. Just so you know.
你出血了，你自己也知道
People have told me that you and I look a lot alike,
有人说你和我长得很像
so I wanted to see for myself.
所以我想自己来瞧瞧
I'm gonna take a piss.
我要去撒泡尿
You scared him away, dumbshit.
你把他吓跑了，笨蛋
You're kidding. Five-star Torres likes The View?
开玩笑吧？五星的托雷斯喜欢看“The View”节目？
No, just Joy Behar.
不，他只是喜欢乔伊・贝哈
The good news is she can breast-feed standing up. That's it.
好消息是她可以站着喂奶，就这样
Where does she come up with this shit?
她怎么会想到这种屁话的？
I'm a Star Jones man myself. I love that big bitch.
我自己也是斯妲・琼斯的粉丝，我喜欢那婊子
That was, like, the furthest thing.
那好像是遥不可及的事
I got married so young, so, I mean,
我结婚的时候太年轻了，所以，我是说
they weren't pressuring me, the society was pressuring me...
他们没有压迫我，社会没有压迫我...
Mr. T orres.
托雷斯先生
Us convicts are starting up a football team.
我们犯人正在组织一支橄榄球队
Not interested.
没兴趣
We're playing the guards.
我们和看守比赛
Walk away.
走开
Good idea.
好主意
0 for 2.
两个人都不成
You're putting the pressure on her right now.
你现在就在压迫她
Show's over, amigo.
演出结束了，朋友
I still got 15 minutes of Joy Behar.
我还有15分钟可以看乔伊・贝哈
Well, I'm cutting you short. Back to your cell, asswipe.
我把你的时间扣了，回牢房去，混蛋
Hey, white boy.
嘿，白人小子
Cherryhead gonna play?
切里海德要打球吗？
Yes, he is.
对，他会打的
Crewe, don't forget, I'm gonna be open.
克鲁，别忘了我会得到空档的
Green 40! Hut!
绿队40！哈！
Damn!
该死！
Brucie. Brucie. You all right? You breathing?
布鲁西，布鲁西。你还好吧？你还有气吗？
I got a bird. His name is Ronnie.
我有一只鸟，他叫罗尼
Well, tell Ronnie you got knocked the fuck out.
哦，告诉罗尼，你被干翻了
Wow, no bullshit. Real football? Against the guards?
哇，别开玩笑。真要打橄榄球？和看守对战？
Full contact.
真刀真枪
Captain Knauer is their quarterback?
科纳瓦队长是他们的四分卫？
- Yep. - So I get to tackle him?
- 对？ - 那我可以擒抱他了？
Yeah. You can either tackle him or hit him over the head with that hammer.
对，你可以擒抱他，也可以拿锤子砸他脑袋
I wanna hurt him. Not kill him.
我只想弄伤他，不想宰了他
Let's get out of here before that thing bites somebody.
咱们还是快出去吧，免得那东西咬人
All right. We'll see you and your pet iguana at practice.
好，那就在练习场上见你和你的小鬣蜥吧
Down, set!
蹲下，预备！
Hut! Hut!
哈！哈！
Hey!
嘿！
- Hit me. - Get rid of it.
- 给我 - 解决掉那家伙
Get rid of it!
解决掉那家伙！
He didn't get rid of it.
他没有解决掉那家伙
Sacked your ass.
抱倒你这混蛋了
Somebody's gotta get open, guys.
应该有人跑到空档
You got hammered by the hammer.
你被大锤砸翻了
I think I felt it on my leg. We gotta get some speed, man.
我是绊倒了，我们得找些有速度的人
What'd you expect? You got no brothers out there.
你指望什么？在这里没人帮得了你
What are you talking about? We got Switowski.
你说什么？我们还有斯韦托斯基呢
Switowski? That's one brother.
斯韦托斯基？那算一个
That's a lonely nigga. This ain't hockey.
只有一个黑鬼，这可不行
You want some speed, you know where to go.
要找有速度的人，你知道该上哪儿
Hey, yo, check out this fake Slim Shady, man.
嘿，瞧瞧这冒牌的痞子阿姆
I knew you couldn't resist my shit.
我知道你不能拒绝我的东西
I got the shakes that'll make you quake.
我有混合饮料，美得让你灵魂出窍
I got the fries that'll cross your eyes.
我有炸薯条，美得让你喜上眉梢
I got the burgers that'll--
我有汉堡包，美得让你--
I just got burgers.
我就是有汉堡包嘛
I'm all right. Thank you.
很好，谢谢你
Just wanted to talk to you fellas about possibly joining the football team.
我只是想跟你们说说加入橄榄球队的事
The only game we'd play with you is
我们只会跟你玩一种游戏，那就是
Slap the Point-Shaving White Boy Till He Cries Like a Baby-Back Bitch.
狠抽打假球的白人小子让他哭得像个宝贝臭婊
Baby-back bitch, baby-back bitch Baby-back bitch
宝贝臭婊，宝贝臭婊，宝贝臭婊
- That's a big-ass robot. - Yeah.
- 真是个大傻机器人 - 啊
You gonna help me out here?
你帮我个忙，出去一下好吗？
Thank you, Half-a-Star.
谢谢，半颗星
Just so you know, we are playing the guards.
你们也知道，我们要和看守比赛
That ain't a team. That's just a bunch of dumb rednecks
那不是球队，只不过是一帮呆瓜
giving themselves excuses to grab each other.
找了借口互相乱打而已
This guy must be quite the athlete, huh?
这位先生肯定是正宗运动员喽？
You risk bringing your ass in the jungle because you know I am.
你胆敢闯进这块地盘来是因为你认识我
Yeah, so you'd beat me in a game of one-on-one, right?
对，所以你会在一对一的比赛里打败我，是吗？
- What? - I think it's time for you to get stepping.
- 什么？ - 我看你该走了
How's this, though? One game.
这样好吗？就比一场
I beat you, you guys play for the team. You beat me, I'll leave you alone.
我赢了你，你的人就替球队打球 你赢了我，我就再也不来烦你
Take that. Take that, Deac.
应战，应战，迪克
This fool ain't nothing but a thing, baby.
这傻瓜有种，宝贝
- Ball, dog. - Ball up!
- 球，哥们 - 球来了！
Can Crewe play ball?
克鲁会打篮球吗？
He's a natural athlete.
他是天生的运动员
So is Greg Louganis, but I bet you he'd get his ass whupped out here.
格雷格・路加尼斯也是，不过我打赌他会完胜的
- Game's 1 1. Call your own fouls. - Okay.
- 打11分。有犯规你要自己喊 - 好的
- Come on, come on. - Give it to him, Deac!
- 上啊上啊 - 给他点厉害尝尝，迪克！
Did I get you?
我伤到你了？
No, that was clean.
没有，不算什么
He'll be all right. Call his mama.
他没事，叫他妈妈来
- If I foul you, tell me, dog. - Okay, baby.
- 假如我对你犯规，就告诉我 - 好的，宝贝
Take this f-- Take this foul.
尝尝这个犯规-- 尝尝这个犯规
What happened there? I think it's my ball, right?
怎么回事？我看这应该是我的球吧？
All right.
好吧
Get up! Get up, Deac!
起来！起来，迪克！
Come on, Paul!
加油，保罗！
- Calm down. - What?
- 冷静点 - 什么？
Now, don't stir up the brothers, now. Come on.
别把弟兄们煽动起来，好啦
Come on, Deacon!
上啊，迪肯！
Did I get you, dog?
我伤到你了吗，哥们？
Hell, no, baby. That was clean. Good D.
没有，宝贝，那不算什么，防得好
I thought he didn't wanna get hurt.
我以为他不想受伤呢
It ain't about getting hurt. It's about pride.
那不是受伤的问题，是自尊心
I bet you he's pretty proud right now.
他现在肯定觉得很自豪
It ain't easy being cheesy!
做个下流胚也不容易！
Did I get you? Did I get you?
我伤到你了？我伤到你了？
- No, I think I'm okay, baby. - I didn't get you, did l?
- 不，我没事，宝贝 - 我没有伤到你，是吧？
That's traveling, bitch.
是你滑倒了，王八蛋
You keep coming, huh?
你还想来吗？
Game point, baby. How you want the game put up?
到赛点了，宝贝，你希望比赛的高潮是怎样？
Foul.
犯规
That was a bullshit call!
真是混蛋哨！
My court, my ball.
我的球场，我的球
All right, y'all. Let Deac speak!
好了，各位。让迪克来说！
Nice spanking that ass, dog.
揍得你很爽，小子
- Now, get stepping. - Hold up.
- 现在走吧 - 等一下
Y'all got a running back?
你们有跑锋吗？
Not any good ones.
没有好的
No disrespect, Deac...
我不想冒犯你，迪克...
...but any man that can take that kind of beating out here,
...不过吃了这种打都能抗住的人
I can't wait to see what he can do in a contact sport.
我很想看看他在身体接触运动里能干什么
Shit, I'm in.
妈的，我加入
Man, give me that cheeseburger. You acting like a real McAsshole.
把那汉堡包给我，你真是个王八蛋
Cheeseburger, he wants to run with the white boys, we will let him.
汉堡包，他要跟这白人小子走，就让他走
Let's do this.
来吧
Earl Megget.
厄尔・麦吉特
Well, we didn't get the whole chocolate bar, but we got a Hershey's Kiss.
好啊，我们没弄到整个巧克力店 但是得到了一块好时巧克力
I'll take it.
我接受
Let's get this over with, rookie, I'm starving.
咱们快点结束吧，菜鸟，我饿坏了
Fresh meat, boys! Fresh meat!
鲜肉，小伙子们！鲜肉！
Down, set!
蹲下，预备！
Battle, you're a psycho!
班涛，你是个神经病！
Tony, you're a fat shit! Hut!
托尼，你是个肥猪！哈！
Holy shit!
我靠！
Get him!
截住他！
Ran right out of your shoes, huh? Hey, manager, don't you think
鞋都跑掉了吗？嘿，经理，你看是不是可以
we can get our new star running back a decent pair of cleats?
给我们新的明星跑锋弄双像样的防滑鞋？
Yeah. I think I got a cousin that drives a truck for Reebok.
好啊，我有个表哥是给锐步开车的
It's cool, man. I never had shoes growing up noway.
太好了，老兄。小点也没关系，还没有我撑不大的鞋
- I'll be all right for now. - Oh, okay.
- 现在我可好了 - 哦，好
Get your country ass back in the huddle.
你这乡下小子快去集合
That boy got some slave feet, you see that?
那小子光脚跑得特别快，你看见了吧？
Defense! Huddle up over there!
防守！到那边集合！
Paul. Paul.
保罗，保罗
Hey, ladies. How's it hanging?
嘿，女士们。在那边干什么？
- Tell him. - I'm gonna say something to him.
- 告诉他 - 我有话和你说
I just wanted to let you know I am your biggest fan.
我就是想让你知道，我是你的头号崇拜者
And I will be cheering my jailhouse boobies off for you at game day.
到比赛那天我会拼命给你加油，把这牢房也掀掉
I appreciate that. Thank you.
我很感激，谢谢你
Paul.
保罗
I appreciate you.
我也很感激你
Okay, thanks. I'm glad to know that.
好的，谢谢。听你这么说我很高兴
Okay, are you done now?
好，你们完事了吧？
What's wrong with you? Jealous because I don't cheer for you anymore?
你出什么毛病了？ 我不给你加油你就吃醋了？
I don't know what you're talking about, freak show.
我才不知道你在说什么，变态
Whatever, back freckles.
随你怎么说，麻皮背
Oh, yeah, back freckles. She's making up shit now.
对，麻皮背，她在胡言乱语
I'm gonna get some water.
我要去喝点水
That feature interview worked better than I thought.
那次专访的效果比我预料的还好
I just got off the phone with ESPN2.
我刚和ESPN2通了电话
They want to televise the football game.
他们想要电视转播这场橄榄球赛
Guards, cons, Paul Crewe, it's compelling stuff.
看守、囚犯、保罗・克鲁，这些都是吸引眼球的题材
Lots of human interest.
人们兴趣浓厚啊
Don't do that in here.
别在这里做这个
Television.
电视
Dandridge, do you think that might help my visibility
丹德里奇，你看这能不能帮我
with the registered voters of this fine state?
提高在本州选民中的知名度？
Oh, yes.
哦，会的
The freak is back!
怪物回来了！
Hey, hey. It's me again.
嘿，嘿。我又来了
You know, if I take this half down, we could play together.
你知道，要是我把这半边桌子放下来，我们就可以一起玩
I'm just gonna take this half down.
那我就把它放下来了
Don't worry. Don't worry. I got another ball.
别担心，别担心，我还有一个球
It's okay.
没问题的
You wanna serve?
你想发球吗？
I'll serve.
我来发球
Really good news. We started a football team.
有个很好的消息，我们组织了一支橄榄球队
You like football?
你喜欢橄榄球吗？
It's kind of like Ping-Pong.
和乒乓球有点像
Only the ball's a little bigger and egg-shaped, like my head.
只不过球大一点，是鸡蛋形的，就和我的脑袋一样
Just a joke. Stay calm.
说笑而已，别激动
Give you a good chance to throw people on the ground,
这样你就有个很好的机会把人扔到地上
hurt them like you used to when you were a kid, 10 feet 6 inches ago.
揍他们，就像你小时候那样，在你长成10英尺6英寸以前
We'd be playing the guards.
我们要和看守们比赛
I think Papajohn's their safety.
我想约翰大伯就是他们的安全卫
Turley, nobody gets to me. We'll play more Ping-Pong later, okay?
特利，要是没人冲到我身边，回头我们就再打乒乓球，好吗？
Hut!
哈！
Effective.
很有效
- All right. - He brokeded my nose.
- 好了 - 他把我鼻子打断了
I don't wanna play no more.
我不要再打球了
Hey, hey, hey. Switowski, what are you talking about?
嘿，嘿，嘿，斯韦托斯基，你说什么呢？
This is football. Shit happens.
这是橄榄球啊，受点伤难免的
Paul, he brokeded my nose.
保罗，他把我鼻子打断了
Okay. Stop crying.
好啦，别哭了
All right. We can fix this. Here we go.
好啦，这个我们能治好的，来了
Okay. Good, good.
好，很好，很好
How's it look?
看上去怎样？
How's it look? It looks-- It looks like-- It looks better than before.
看上去怎样？看上去-- 看上去好像--好像比以前更好了
- Really? - Yeah, it's straighter.
- 真的？ - 对，更加直了
More distinguished. Kind of like a young Michael Jackson.
更加漂亮了，有点像年轻时候的麦克尔・杰克逊
I love little Michael.
我爱小麦克尔
That's great. That's great.
那很好，那很好
I think he did it on purpose.
我看他是故意的
No, he didn't.
不，他不是故意的
Okay, maybe he did.
好吧，也可能是
You gotta apologize to him. Come on, Turley.
你该向他道歉，来吧，特利
Say you're sorry.
说对不起
Come on. Say it.
好啦，说吧
He said he's sorry. I got him to say he's sorry.
他说对不起了，我让他说对不起了
Yeah, yeah. We're all impressed.
对，对。我们都很感动
Looking good, gentlemen. Way to work hard.
看来不错，先生们，都很努力
Good practice, Paul! Me and the girls wanna show you
练得真好，保罗！我和姑娘们想让你看看
- what we've been practicing. - Okay, hit me.
- 我们的练习成果 - 好啊，让我看看
Come on, let's go. One, two, three.
来吧，上了。一、二、三
Give me a...
给我一个...
D, D, give me a I I, I, give me a C
D，D，给我一个I I，I，给我一个C
C, give me a--
C，给我一个--
All right, all right! I got it. Just save it for the game.
好了，好了！我看到了，到比赛时候再亮出来吧
Don't act like you ain't want to see more, Brucie!
别装得不想看似的，布鲁西！
- Yeah, you wish, pal. - No, you wish I'd kiss you again,
- 对，是你想要，朋友 - 不，你是想要我再吻你
because your breath smell like eight cans of shark shit.
你的口臭就像八泡鲨鱼屎一样
I wouldn't touch her with a 10-foot pole.
就是用十英尺长的杆子碰她我都恶心
- What's he talking about? - He's a freak.
- 他说什么？ - 他是个变态
Run, Forrest, run!
跑啊，阿甘，跑啊！ （《阿甘正传》里的台词）
That's how a white man plays guitar.
白人就是这样弹吉他的
Captain, he said he had some info.
队长，他说他有些情报
You guys have "Halo 2." I didn't even think that was out yet.
你们在玩“Halo 2”，我以为这还没出呢
Focus. Turn the music off!
正经点。把音乐关了！
Yeah, captain. You know them convicts?
好，队长，你知道那些犯人吧？
They're starting to get some serious players.
他们现在有些很像样的球员了
But their biggest threat? A running back. Megget.
可是他们最大的威胁是谁？是一个跑锋，麦吉特
- He's good? - He's fast.
- 他很棒？ - 他很快
He's really, really fast.
他非常非常快
I mean, he's so fast, he makes fast people look not fast.
我是说，他太快了，很快的人在他面前都显得不快了
I got it, he's fast.
我明白了，他很快
Now, why don't you show us your speed and get your pyro ass out of here.
那么现在让我们看看你的速度，快从这里滚出去吧
Yes, sir. Here I go. I'm sorry.
是，长官。我这就走，对不起
Any books you'd recommend, inmate?
有什么书可推荐吗，囚犯？
No, sir.
没有，长官
Not much of a reader.
我书读得不多
Oh, come on, now, maggot. I've seen you in here reading before.
得了，蛆虫，我以前经常看见你在这里读书
You requested this detail. Isn't that right?
这个活也是你自己要求的，对吗？
No. It's the quiet time I like, sir.
不，我只是喜欢清静，长官
Maybe you'd like to read this.
也许你会喜欢看这本书
What the hell kind of bullshit book is that?
这是什么狗屁书？
It's historical. Sir.
这是历史，长官
Now, why would he want to read a book about a four-eyed nigger?
为什么他会喜欢看关于一个四眼黑鬼的书？
Does the N word offend you, nigger?
这个词是不是让你不高兴了？黑鬼？
No, sir.
没有，长官
Sorry about that.
对不起
You mind fetching these books for me, boy?
帮我捡一下书你不介意吧，小子？
No, sir.
不介意，长官
Just pick them up. Put them on the table.
把它们捡起来，放到桌上
There you go.
给您
You forgot one.
你忘了一本
Bet you'd like to hit us, huh?
你肯定很想打我们吧，唔？
Hit you, sir? No.
打你们？长官？不
Y'all my friends.
你们都是我的朋友
Pick these up.
把它们捡起来
Go!
上！
Hit me! I'm open! I'm open!
给我！我这里空了！我这里空了！
Come on! We got one week before we play that game.
搞什么！我们还有一个星期就要打比赛了
We can't complete a pass yet.
我们现在还是连传球都做不好
- Megget can't run the ball every play. - I know, coach.
- 麦吉特总不能每一次都带球跑 - 我知道，教练
What the hell is he smiling at?
他到底在笑什么？
This better be on the up and up.
这比赛最好是光明正大的
I guarantee it.
我可以保证
Let's do this shit.
那咱们干吧
There goes the neighborhood.
咱们的邻居来了
Now I'll never get to play.
现在我再也没机会打球了
Did you see that? Did you see that? The Deac is here!
你们看见了吧？你们看见了吧？迪克在此！
Nice.
很好
Okay, we seal off here, seal off here.
好，我们封住这里，封住这里
- Cheeseburger. - Yeah.
- 汉堡包 - 在
You're just gonna chip this guy...
你要把这家伙放倒...
That stings.
痛啊
It's nothing a Quarter Pounder can't fix.
没有大汉堡治不了的伤
With cheese on it?
上面有奶酪吗？
Hut!
哈！
Man, that boy would catch a cold in the desert. Here you go.
那小子在沙漠里都会得感冒，给你
- Everything's looking up. - Yeah.
- 看来一切顺利 - 是啊
Still got one more pain in the ass to deal with.
还有点小疮疤需要解决
All right, what do you say? How about a little best ball?
好，你们说怎样？要不要来点好球比赛？
No, I hate that bullshit. Everyone play their own damn ball.
不要，我讨厌比赛，大家各打各的球吧
Holy shit, is that Paul Crewe?
我靠，那是保罗・克鲁吗？
How do you like that, boys? The MVP coming to kiss my ass.
你们觉得怎样？MVP来亲我的屁股了
So, what's on your mind, Paul?
那么，你有什么想法，保罗？
Got a problem with inmate Unger.
关于犯人昂格尔的问题
- Is he on your little squad? - I believe he's on your little squad.
- 他是你队里的人吗？ - 我相信他是你队里的人
Mr. Crewe, would you mind if we had a picture? Please?
克鲁先生，拍张照片你不介意吧？好吗？
That's up to the warden.
听典狱长的
- Damn it. All right. - Rewound it. Did everything.
- 该死，好吧 - 卷过胶卷了，全都准备好了
- The flash is ready. - You don't need a flash. It's daylight.
- 闪光灯也准备好了 - 用不着闪光灯，现在是大白天
Oh, my bad. I just want a good picture.
哦，是我不对，我只想拍得好一点
You know, I think you had sex with my wife before I married her.
要知道，我认为我老婆在跟我结婚前和你上过床
- Sorry about that. - Oh, hell, no.
- 很抱歉 - 啊，才不呢
If she's hot enough to have a one-nighter with a pro football player,
假如她漂亮到可以和职业橄榄球选手搞一夜情
I must be doing all right.
那我肯定是赚到了
Okay, here we go.
好，咱们来吧
- Sergeant Engleheart? - Yes, warden.
- 恩格尔哈特警长？ - 是，典狱长
Would you step out of the picture, please?
到镜头外面去好吗？
Yes, sir.
是，长官
- His wife has got the hottest ass. - Great.
- 他老婆有最性感的屁股 - 太棒了
Just cut to the chase, shall we?
咱们还是开门见山吧
You don't actually think you have a chance of winning, now, do you?
你其实并没觉得你有机会赢，是吗？
We're gonna get our asses handed to us.
我们跳不出你的手心
I know it. You know it. I just don't want my players to know it.
我知道，你也知道，我只是不想让我的队员知道
Your players?
你的队员？
Just when I thought I had you all figured out.
我还以为我已经把你都摸透了呢
- What does that mean? - In the time you've been here,
- 这是什么意思？ - 在你进来以后
you haven't made or received one telephone call.
你没有打过或接过一个电话
You haven't opened so much as a single shred of mail.
你没有拆过一封信
What do you give a damn about those slimeballs?
你怎么会在乎这些混球？
You never cared about anybody in your entire life.
你这辈子从没关心过任何人
Well, maybe I finally found that sense of family
哦，也许我终于找到了
I been yearning for since I'm a baby.
从小就渴望的家庭温暖
And gosh almighty,
而且对上帝起誓
my new family and l would sure appreciate it
如果你把昂格尔赶出球场
if you got Unger off the field. You hear?
我的新家人和我都会很感激，你听到了吗？
Sergeant Engleheart.
恩格尔哈特警长
Thank you.
谢谢你
Oh, and as for your request...
哦，至于你的请求...
...you'll have my answer soon enough.
...你很快就会得到我的答复
Did it rain last night?
昨天晚上下雨了？
Not a drop.
一滴都没下
Son of a bitch.
狗娘养的
All right, boys.
好吧，小伙子们
The warden is trying to break our spirit.
典狱长是想让我们泄气
He thinks we're gonna skip practice today,
他以为我们今天会放弃训练
wait for the field to dry, make it up tomorrow.
等场地变干，明天再说
You know what? Who gives a shit?
你们知道吗？谁在乎这个？
Three days till game time. We can handle it.
离比赛还有三天 我们能对付
But let me say this:
不过听我说：
That old man flooding this field tells me something.
那个拿水浇球场的老头 让我知道了一件事
The guy is scared.
这家伙害怕了
Scared of you sick, degenerate convicts.
害怕你们这些有问题的、堕落的囚犯
And you know what?
你们知道吗？
He should be.
他应该害怕
Because I got news for you guys.
因为我要告诉你们一个消息
We're gonna win this thing.
我们要赢
Did he say "win"?
他说了“赢”吗？
What's it gonna be, boys?
现在怎么办，小伙子们？
Do we go back to our cells, call it a day?
我们是回到牢房去，就这样过一天？
Or do we get ourselves ready for the greatest ass-kicking fiesta
还是为了橄榄球历史上 最伟大的造反节日
in the history of football?
做准备？
I'll leave it up to you guys.
由你们来决定
Hey. You're part of the goddamn team.
嘿，你也是这混蛋球队的一员
Get your point-shaving ass in there.
你这假球分子也去吧
You got it.
说得对
I guess that asshole Hazen wants to play dirty.
我猜海岑那个混蛋在比赛时会使阴招
- We all convicts, right? - Right.
- 我们都是囚犯，对吧？ - 对
Maybe it's time we started acting like it.
说不定现在是我们 拿出囚犯样子的时候了
Right here. Right here.
就是这儿，就是这儿
Take it, Deac.
拿着，迪克
Let's see which guards have some broken bones.
咱们看看哪些看守曾经骨折过
Yeah!
耶！
Shoes, nigga!
鞋子，黑鬼！
Check this out. These be brass knuckles. They damn near old as me.
瞧这个，黄铜关节指套 差不多和我一样年纪
Hut!
哈！
That's perfect, Cheeseburger! Never been better.
棒极了，汉堡包！ 再好没有了
Good ball. Good ball.
好球，好球
Okay.
好
- Who we gonna crush? - The guards!
- 我们要揍扁谁？ - 看守们！
- Who we gonna kill?
- 我们要宰掉谁？
- Who we gonna kiss? - The guards!
- 我们要亲吻谁？ - 看守们！
Gotcha.
中招了
Lights out!
熄灯！
Good night, ladies.
晚安，女士们
- Yo, Crewe! - Yes, Mr. Caretaker.
- 喂，克鲁！ - 唔，凯尔泰克先生
Check your toilet. There should be a little surprise in there for you.
看看你的马桶。里面有给你的 小惊喜
You took a shit in my toilet?
你在我马桶里放了大便？
No, that's the surprise I left in Brucie's toilet.
不是，那是我扔在布鲁西的马桶里的
- You got something else. - All right.
- 给你的是别的东西 - 好吧
Well, would you look at this.
哦，瞧瞧这个
A bottle of Ketel One and two glasses?
一瓶Ketel One（伏特加酒） 和两个杯子？
Now, what would I need two for?
为什么我需要两个杯子？
Just shut up and pour me a drink, bitch.
闭嘴，给我也倒一杯
- Man, who taught you to be so cool? - My mama.
- 老兄，谁把你教得这么酷的？ - 我妈
Now, when I get out of here, I don't want you to get all Hollywood on us.
等我从这儿出去了，我也不要 你把整个好莱坞的人都找来
I want you to meet her.
我只要你和她见一面
Here, look at my girl. She's your biggest fan.
给，瞧瞧我的姑娘 她是你的头号崇拜者
Your mom's beautiful.
你妈妈很漂亮
And you, you are ugly.
你嘛，你很丑
Thank you. Got it.
谢谢，我知道了
Here's to...
这是敬...
...the first friend I've had in I don't know how long.
...我也不知道是多久以来的 第一个朋友
Hey, I thought I was your friend, Paul.
嘿，我以为我也是你朋友呢，保罗
You are, Switowski. Just finish your coloring book and go back to sleep.
你是，斯韦托斯基。赶快看完你 那本图画书，睡觉去吧
Okay.
好
And here's to having one of these with you on the outside,
这个是希望在今后三五年里的什么时候
sometime in the next three to five years.
和你一起在外面喝一杯
- Yo, Crewe. - Yes, sir.
- 喂，克鲁 - 唔，先生
You being a ex-football player and all,
你以前是橄榄球运动员
I'm sure you got a lot of hot ass on the outside.
在外面肯定有很多漂亮姘头
Well, let's not forget I wasn't the most popular guy out there.
喂，别忘了，我在外面 还不是最受欢迎的
Don't give me that shit.
别说这种屁话
O.J. chopped his wife's head off and still got some ass.
辛普森把他老婆的脑袋都砍掉了 照样能找到姘头
Yeah.
哈哈哈
My mama taught me not to kiss and tell. Now, go to sleep.
我妈妈教我不要找了女人还到处 声张。现在睡觉吧
All right. I got one more question to ask you.
好吧，我还有一个问题要问你
Okay. What is it?
好的，是什么？
Why'd you shave those points?
为什么你要打假球？
Didn't you read the papers? I'm innocent.
你没看报纸吗？ 我是清白的
Yeah. Ain't we all?
对。我们大家不都是吗？
Yo, Crewe, what would you say
喂，克鲁，要是我帮你 把看守们去年比赛的录像搞来
if I could get you film from the guards' games last year?
你会怎么说？
I would say that's incredible, but how?
我会说那真神了，可你怎么搞？
Thanks, gentlemen.
谢谢，先生们
The warden will be done with him in 15 minutes.
典狱长和他只要15分钟就完事
- We can handle him. - Yes, ma'am.
- 我们能对付他 - 是的，太太
Then you're gonna, ma'am.
那我们走了，太太
Nice job.
干得好
I can't tell you how much this means to me. Thank you, Lynette.
我都说不出这对我有多重要 谢谢你，莉奈特
Now Nate can study all the guards' formations.
现在内特可以研究看守们的所有阵形了
Not so fast, sugar bear.
别那么快，小糖熊
You gotta earn them.
你得付报酬
We only got 1 5 minutes,
我们只有15分钟
but, sunshine, we're gonna make them all count.
但是亲爱的，我们不会浪费 每一分钟
One more, please?
再来一杯好吗？
Let's go.
走吧
- Quiet down. Guys. - Let's go.
- 静一静，哥们 - 开始吧
Before we watch the guards' game film from last season,
在看看守们去年的比赛录像之前
we have a special presentation from our very own Mr. Paul Crewe.
我们的保罗・克鲁先生 要给大家送上一个特别节目
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
What's going on?
怎么回事？
Now I gotta relive this shit?
我又要再体验一遍这个？
You can say this, my man's a team player!
你可以说，我的朋友很会配合！
You know what they say. Once you go gray, there ain't no other way!
你知道他们怎么说：你一旦变老 就没有别的路了！
Hey, hey, hey. Brucie! Brucie! I'm glad you think that's funny,
嘿，嘿，嘿，布鲁西！布鲁西！ 你觉得这个好玩，我很高兴
because I got something pretty funny to show you guys.
因为我有些很好玩的东西给你们看
Tony, hit it. You're gonna like this.
托尼，来吧。你们会喜欢的
- What the hell is this? - What? It's good. It keeps going.
- 这到底是什么？ - 什么？很好啊，继续
- Hi. - Here I am.
- 嗨 - 我在这儿
Turn this shit off. Turn it off.
关掉，关掉
No!
不行！
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Very funny. Trick photography.
对，对，对。很好玩 这是特技做出来的
Nothing happened.
没发生什么事
I was showing a little wrestling move. That's all.
我是在表演摔跤，就这么回事
Knock it off!
暂停！
It's time we took a look at what we came here to see
趁着看守还没回来
before the guards come back.
我们该看看正经东西了
The first film is the guards' offense against Texas Southern.
第一个录像是看守队 对德克萨斯南方队的进攻
Now, as you can see, they're running a standard wishbone.
你们可以看到 他们用的是标准的叉骨阵形
So you're telling me that these animals are watching our game films.
你是说这些畜牲在看我们的比赛录像
- Is that right? - Yes, sir, boss.
- 对吗？ - 是的，老大
They got all last season.
上赛季的比赛他们全搞到了
Seems to me that we ought to do something about this.
看来我们应该有所行动
What do you want me to do?
你要我干什么？
You're the criminal. Be creative.
你是罪犯。发挥想象力吧
But on game day, if I so much as--
不过在比赛那天，假如我这么--
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
I don't know. I've had hot flashes all shift,
我不知道 我身上老是发热
and now my nipples are killing me.
现在我的乳头又让我难过得要命
Why are we talking about your nipples?
我们干吗要关心你的乳头？
We're not. Just go do what you're doing there.
不用。接着做你的事吧
Guys.
哥们
I want Crewe finished.
我要让克鲁完蛋
Yes, sir. You give me the inspiration, sir. I got something for him.
是，长官。你给了我灵感，长官 我有办法对付他
Hut!
哈！
Everybody!
各位！
Huddle up!
集合！
Every day we've been taking shit, for a long time.
我们天天受罪，已经熬了很久
Tomorrow, payback. Now, think about that for a second.
明天，就要报仇 现在，稍微想一想吧
- What time is it? - Game time!
- 什么时候？ - 比赛时候！
Tomorrow, 1 2:00, the bus leaves. Don't be late!
明天12:00，公车就会走，别迟到了！
Where the hell is Caretaker?
凯尔泰克到底在哪儿？
I don't know.
不知道
A gift for you, Mr. Crewe.
给你的礼物，克鲁先生
How does he listen to that cracker shit?
他怎么听这种狗屁玩意？
We're here deep in the heart of toothless country,
我们现在是在一片不毛之地的中心
coming to you from a simple Texas high school stadium
从一个简陋的德克萨斯 高中体育馆向您直播
that's been retrofitted for the big event.
这个体育馆已经为一件大事而作了翻新
Now, when my man T ravis tried to drag me out here, I said,
当我的同事特拉维斯把我拖到 这里来的时候，我说：
"What are you, brain-dead from talking to too many Raider fans?
“你怎么回事？对袭击者队的球迷 采访太多，脑子坏掉了吗？
It's not going to work."
这里不能做节目的。”
But the fact of the matter is, this could shape up as an epic day.
但事实是，这里可能将发生 载入史册的大事
Hot-dog vendors, high-powered rifles, I love the combination.
热狗摊主、大威力步枪 我喜欢这种组合
And apparently so do the fans.
并且球迷也如此疯狂
Hey, shitheads! Listen up!
嗨！猪头们！
Everybody on their feet for the warden.
立正！典狱长要讲话
Anthony, wow. You can sit down.
安东尼，你还是坐着吧
Thank God.
谢天谢地
Gentlemen, Texas marshals have been kind enough
先生们，得克萨斯州警方 很友善的
to supply us with a dozen of their finest sharpshooters.
为我们提供了十二个神枪手
So for those of you thinking of mingling with the civilians
你们如果想趁乱混到人群中
or trying to make a break for it,
或者是想逃走
you will be shot.
就等着吃子弹吧
In the head.
子弹会正中头部
Now, let's all go out there and have some fun!
让我们出去运动吧
Crewe! I'll see you on the field!
克鲁！赛场见
I think he's in love with you.
我觉得他爱上你了
All right, listen up.
好了，大家听着
I know it's hard to get psyched for the game without Caretaker being here.
我知道凯尔退克不在这儿 大家很难鼓足士气
But somehow that sick, skinny bastard
但是这个小东西
found a way to get us all fired up from beyond the grave.
在阴间也会给我们打气
Caretaker's last gift to us.
凯尔退克给我们的最后礼物
Battle, I presume this is yours.
班涛，我觉得这个是给你的
I still don't think that's big enough.
我觉得还不够大
- That's it? - No, that ain't it.
- 就这些？ - 不是，还有
Caretaker said he'd find us some gear to wear.
凯尔泰克说过他会弄些 适合我们穿的
I think he found us a name too.
而且他把我们的名字也 弄上去了
Mean Machine! Mean Machine!
邪恶战车！邪恶战车！ 邪恶战车！
Good afternoon and welcome to a very special edition of ESPN football.
下午好，欢迎收看ESPN体育台 这场特殊的橄榄球赛
As today, the semipro Allenville Federal Prison guards
今天比赛将在来自阿伦维尔联邦监狱 狱警组成的半职业球队
will be taking on the very prisoners they guard.
与他们所看守的犯人之间展开
And with this special game, folks, comes a special broadcast,
这个特殊的比赛当然 也由特殊的主持人来播报
as I'm joined in the booth by Baby Face Bob.
所以我和娃娃脸鲍勃 一起来到这个播音间
Say hi to the folks, Bob-O.
跟大家问个好，鲍勃
Chris, we went to a commercial.
克里斯，插入广告
This job, Bob, it's a lot of give and take.
节目过程中 我们应该互相交换意见
So when I bring you in, don't be afraid to talk to the folks.
所以我把话题转给你的时候 大胆的对听众说吧说吧
Unless you don't want to.
除非你不原意
And here come the cons,
现在出场的是囚犯队
Ied by former NFL MVP quarterback Paul Crewe.
领队是前美国橄榄球协会最有价值 球员四分卫保罗克鲁
Holy shit. Hey, hey, hey.
天啊！！乖乖！
Well, hello. How are you?
嗨！你们好！
Back away from the girls!
离姑娘们远点！
- Hey, now. - Call me!
- 快点 - 给我打电话！
What the hell are you dressed up for?
你怎么也穿成这样？
Hey, I didn't spend 14 years in the joint just to watch this game.
你以为我花14年呆在监狱 只是为了看看比赛？
And there in the high-security bleachers
那边是高度警戒的露天看台
are the good-behavior cons, along with their...
以及举止端庄的囚犯
...cheerleaders?
还有……貌似拉拉队员……
We're the mean machine Don't mean to dis you
我们是邪恶战车
We're gonna kick your ass And then we'll kiss you
我们要打败你 然后给你香吻
Hey! Ho! What?
嗨嗨哈哈！
I didn't do it!
不是我干的
- What's that? - Did you see that?
- 快看 - 怎么回事？
Damn it!
真见鬼
Papajohn's at the 20, the 10. And he will score.
帕约翰正在二十码处，十码了 他要得分了
Sweet dreams, bitch.
做个美梦吧！贱种
That's a 90-yard return.
这是一次90码的回攻
And I gotta tell you, the cons seem more interested in hitting the guards
说句老实话我觉得 囚犯似乎更喜欢打狱警
than tackling the ball carrier.
而不是擒抱的方式来 阻止对方前进
Hey, Mom. Hey, Dad. Thanks for picking me up from school.
嗨！老妈，老爸 谢谢你们把我从学校接回来
And here comes the big story of the day.
今天最大的新闻是
Paul Crewe, serving a three-year sentence,
保罗克鲁 正在他的三年服刑期内
hasn't played since he was banned from the NFL six years ago.
这是他六年前被美国橄榄球协会 禁赛以来第一次正式出席比赛
Center, shift it! Shift it!
中位，换位
Hey, Sasquatch!
嗨！大脚怪兽
Crewe drops back to pass. Turley's leaving him unprotected.
克鲁背传 特里没有及时防卫
Fumble!
失球
Goddamn it.
真见鬼
That's gonna be a personal foul on the big guy.
这个大家伙要吃记侵人犯规了
And this is certainly an inauspicious start for the cons.
囚犯队真是出师不利
Come here! All right! You got him. Now, protect me!
好了，你摆平他了 现在好好坐我的后卫
Let's go! Hold them!
我们上！压倒他们
And here comes Knauer and that big offensive unit for the guards.
现在的形势是科纳瓦和 狱警进攻小队
Eighty-six.
八十六
Back to your cell.
回你的笼子去
Knauer has Potter wide open. Touchdown, guards.
囚犯们的后防空虚 狱警得分
- Son of a bitch! - And in the first 90 seconds,
仅在开场90秒
the guards are up by two touchdowns.
狱警的比分扶摇直上 因为两个攻方持球得分（各6分）
This one looks like it could be over early.
看上去这个比赛会速战速决
Sorry.
抱歉
What are we celebrating for?! It's 1 4-nothing!
你们高兴什么？ 这是14：0的大比分
You guys wanna beat these assholes, do it on the scoreboard!
你们要真想摆平那些混蛋 应该在记分板上体现
Are you okay? Oh, God, you're not hurt, are you?
你没事吧？ 天啊，你受伤了？
Jesus, you sound like my mother.
你怎么婆婆妈妈的！
Listen, if you wanna cry, you go ahead and cry. I'll cry with you.
你要是想哭就尽情地哭吧 我会陪着你哭的
Get off me! Get back out there and kick some ass!
滚开，回赛场上去 好好教训他们
Why are you yelling at me? All I did was care!
你怎么对我大喊大叫的？ 我只是关心你
Look! A broken leg will heal.
打断腿可以医好
A loss to the Mean Machine lasts forever.
但是如果邪恶战车输了 那将是永久的耻辱
Sorry, guys.
对不起，伙计们
Yeah, yeah. Me too.
我也很抱歉
All right. Now, let's get started!
好了，我们重新开始
Now, get the hell out there! Let's go!
上场要给他们点颜色
Way to go! Way to go!
这边，这边
There's the first sign of life from the cons.
这可是囚犯队有史以来 第一次出现的好迹象
Let's see if Paul "Motley" Crewe can make something happen.
看看克鲁小丑能做点什么名堂
On first down, Crewe will throw. He's got Deacon wide open.
克鲁要丢球了 他找到迪肯的空当
That's gotta be pass interference.
这个应该是犯规
But the ref is waving it off.
但是裁判示意没事
- What?! - Oh, come on!
怎么回事?
Come on, now. I'm in this hellhole for less than that.
这件事可太不让人舒适
- Be a man and make a call. - You're right.
- 像个男人那样公正判罚 - 没问题
Unsportsmanlike conduct! Eighty-eight black!
黑队88号！无体育道德
What?!
什么？
Come on!
好了
This is baby-back bullshit!
真是垃圾！
- Bullshit, D. - Calm down. Let it go.
冷静，我们继续
Let's call that one a questionable call.
这个可真是个可以的判罚
Blue 42, hut!
蓝色42方案
The give is to Megget. He spins to the outside. Megget has room.
球传给了麦吉特，他转身到外围 位置不错
He's at the 35. The 40.
他到了35码区，40码区
He's brought down hard, by his facemask.
他被人拽倒了 拽的是头盔
What? Oh, come on, man! That was a facemask!
你看到了吗？ 他拽拉我的头盔
- You're not gonna call that? - I saw a clean tackle, sir.
- 这个你也不判罚？ - 我觉得这个正当防守
What you looking at? Are you serious?
你是干什么的？ 你真的这么想？
Tell it to the parole board, criminal.
去你和你的假释审批官争论吧 你这个罪犯
I mean, this is absurd.
这可太荒唐了
We can't win with the refs on the payroll!
我们遇到这种裁判员 根本没有赢的机会
Listen up. I got an idea to end all this bullshit.
我有办法了
Come on, let's all stay up! Come on!
来大家振作
Down, set!
就位
Red 58.
红队58
Cover your man!
掩护你的人
That one hurt my marble sack.
这一计可够他受的
All right!
好了
- You all right? - Yeah.
- 你怎么样？ - 没事
- What down is it? - Fifth.
- 现在该第几次进攻？ - 第五次
- No, no. It would be fourth down. - Okay.
- 算第四次吧 - 好的
What do you think? Should I go for the left nut this time?
你觉得怎么样？ 我这次是不是该左路进攻？
Underneath! Let's go!
向下！开球吧
Ref, you gotta get in the game! Right over here!
裁判你挡着比赛了 你在这个位置比较好
Well, I don't quite get this, but on fourth and 22, the cons are gonna go for it.
我不太清楚， 但是就现在的进攻形势，囚犯队任务艰巨
Down, set!
进攻，就位
Red 58.
红队58
You gotta always protect the McNuggets.
你可得保护好你那“小棒球”
How about from now on, you call a fair game? How's that sound?
从现在开始， 你公平判罚怎么样？
Sounds good.
好吧
Okay. Wet Willie.
不错，润润
Yeah, you like that.
我知道你喜欢
And so the guards will take over
在看过这么一系列荒诞的进攻后
after one of the strangest offensive series I've ever seen.
现在轮到狱警队来进攻了
Okay, boys. We know who doesn't have any balls out there now.
大家都熟悉战场上的情况了吧
Have we got any? Have we got some balls?
我们有信心吗？
- Yeah! - All right! Let's go kick some ass!
- 当然！ - 去吧！打垮他们
Come on, Swit, stand them up, baby.
斯韦托就位
White 50. White 50. Hut, hut, hut!
白队50注意
Knauer, play action. Here comes the blitz.
科纳瓦，行动迅速 带给我们场闪电战
Switowski is so big, it's like being tackled by a Coke machine with legs.
斯韦托斯基真是个大块 他的擒抱防卫看上去就像有腿的可乐售货机
This is fun!
真是有趣
Nice to see you smiling, Bob.
很高兴看到你笑，鲍勃
Thanks, Chris.
谢谢，克里斯
Green 90! Hut!
直达90码
Third and 5, and the give is to Megget.
球传给了麦吉特
He's to the 40, where he'll come up short.
他到了40码线 进攻看来停下了
But look at Turley push the pile.
但是特利想法向前推进
And now Crewe.
克鲁也上了
And that's a first down!
第一次进攻结束
And look out. Boy, somebody better take control of this game soon,
场上情形进入白热化 要是没人来控制
or they're gonna need body bags on the sidelines.
我看要出人命了
Let's go, guys.
来吧，伙计们
Start of the second quarter.
第二次四分之一进攻开始
Cons still down by two touchdowns, but they finally have some momentum.
虽然囚犯队失利两次 但是显然他们并没有失去势头
Crewe with a shovel pass to Megget.
克鲁把球急传给了麦吉特
And Megget scrambles for a first down.
麦吉特的进攻结束
Oh, you fooled me.
你跟我耍花招
- I got you there, didn't l? - You did.
- 你种着了吧 - 是啊
You know, Engleheart, you are the best-looking guy on your team.
恩格尔哈特你是 你队友里长得最好看的一个
You know, Paul, in the midst of all this, for you to say something like that is...
保罗你是这些人中 第一个对我说这些……
Come on, let's go. Let's go, D.
来吧来吧，继续防守
First and 10 at the guards' 35.
这次进攻从35码起
Crewe dumps it over the middle to Deacon Moss.
克鲁把球中传给了迪肯莫斯
And he's hammered at the 17 for a 13-yard pickup, and that's a first down.
而他继续将战线推进了13码
- Hut! - Crewe, trying to get his team
克鲁正极力
on the scoreboard.
刷新比分
He will throw.
他掷出了
And it's caught by Deacon Moss for a touchdown!
迪肯莫斯接住了 而且得分
All right!
太好啦！
And so there'll be no shutout today, as the cons are on the board.
好了他们今天终于有幸 出现在比分牌上了
Quit booing, people. Both teams are trying very hard!
别叹息了 我们两队都尽力打比赛呢
What the hell's wrong with you? Stop acting like a damn cheerleader!
你是怎么回事？ 别把自己当成是啦啦队长
- Sportsmanship, try it. - Shut up.
- 这是运动员精神，你也试试？ - 闭嘴
2:1 1 left in the first half. And Dunham is back in at fullback.
比分2：1上半时还剩一分钟 丹哈姆现在是后卫
And he is a load, at 6'2", 260.
真是重磅出击 他6英尺2英寸260磅
Dunham, breaking tackles.
丹哈姆 突破了对手的擒抱
He refuses to go down.
他继续进攻
But he finally does after a 1 5-yard gain.
最后还是在15码处倒地
That's how a white man runs a football.
你知道为什么只有 白人可以玩转橄榄球吗?
If I was on D, I'd crack you square in that egg-ass head of yours.
如果是我在防守 我会让你更难看
Yeah, but you ain't on D. Are you, bitch?
但是你不是防守队员 小贱货
Switowski! Come here.
斯韦托斯基！过来
Do you know what he said to me in the library?
你知道那个坏蛋 在图书馆怎么说我？
Yes. Him. Out.
没错，让他出局
D, D, defense
防守防守
The cons don't seem to have an answer for Dunham,
看来囚犯队还是没有对抗 丹哈姆的良策
who's averaging close to 12 yards a carry this half.
谁能轻易拉平12比分呢
Green 67.
突进67
Oh, what a hit on Dunham by Switowski.
丹哈姆不敌斯韦托斯基
I think I made him shit himself.
我觉得我摆平他了
- Shit! - I think he just shit himself.
我觉得他被摆平了
Good Lord. This guy shit himself bigtime.
天啊 摆平他可真不容易
See? I told you I made him shit himself!
哈哈！是我摆平他的
Yo! I'll make sure I send them books to the hospital, pimp.
我会去医院送书给他的
And some diapers.
还有尿布
Nineteen seconds. We got a lot of ground to cover.
还有19秒 这里有很多草皮
So you bastards remember that play we practiced in the mud?
你们还记得我们 在泥浆上的训练吗？
What are you talking about? That was some schoolyard bullshit.
泥浆？ 这里是正规的赛场！
Yeah. Let's try some schoolyard bullshit.
那我们就玩点赛场把戏
Come on, D, let's go.
来吧，防守
Down, set! Green 88.
进攻吧88号
The clock starts to run. Crewe hands the ball to Megget. It's a reverse.
时钟开始运转，克鲁把球传给了麦吉特 是反方向的
Cheeseburger Eddy's got it.
汉堡包埃迪拿到了球
Go, baby, go!
前进吧
He laterals to Deacon.
他侧传给迪肯
T ackle him!
阻止他！
To Turley.
传给特里
The clock is running. To Brucie.
时钟继续运转 球传给了布鲁西
Shades of Cal-Stanford.
又给了卡尔-斯坦福
Back to Crewe.
又回到克鲁手里
He tosses to Megget.
他掷给麦吉特
T ackle him!
阻止他
And look at that little Megget run.
看看小麦吉特跑起来的样子
Three seconds left.
还剩3秒了
Yeah! Go!
加油吧！
He could go all the way. Touchdown!
没人拦得住他，得分
Did you see that?!
你们看到了吧？！
Do that sound again.
在那样叫一下
I like that.
我很喜欢
And so, on a miraculous play,
这可真是奇迹般的比赛
the cons end the first half with the score: 14-all.
囚犯队在上半场扳平比分 14平
Bring it in.
注意！
Do you have any idea who's beating you out there?
你们知道你们要输给谁？
This was supposed to be a blowout,
这肯定是爆炸新闻
and they're showing you up in front of the whole nation.
而且整个国家的人都在看着我们
The whole nation!
整个国家
I like it when he's angry.
我喜欢他生气的样子
- I told you! - Way to go, baby, way to go.
- 我跟你说了！ - 这边走
What in the hell do you think you're doing out there?
你觉得你在做什么？
Playing football, sir.
打比赛！
I didn't say nothing about winning.
我可没说让你赢
We're not winning. Not yet.
我们没赢，至少现在
You got yourself in quite a predicament, Mr. Crewe.
你这个给自己找麻烦 克鲁先生
- Is that right? - See, it's just come to my attention
- 是吗？ - 听好了
that inmate Unger has been taken into custody
昂格尔已经因为谋杀凯尔泰克
for the murder of Caretaker.
被特殊监管了
- Good. - Oh, yeah, it's good.
- 很好 - 是的，是件好事
Only thing is, he claims to have an accomplice.
还有件事，他说他有个同伙
Claims you knew all about it.
他说是你是合谋
Hell, he even says you sent Caretaker to your cell.
而且他说是你让凯尔泰克 去你的牢房的
Bullshit.
胡说八道
Captain Knauer says he saw you planning it with Unger.
科纳瓦上尉说他看到你和昂格尔 共同策划整个事件
There's no way that could hold up in court.
这些成不了法庭的证据
Court?
法庭？
Hell, boy, in Allenville, I'm the judge, I'm the jury,
小子！在阿伦维尔会有法律？ 一切都是我说了算
and in your particular case, I'm the executioner.
而且鉴于你的特殊情况 我还可以为你执行死刑
What do you want?
你要怎么样？
I want you to lose.
我要你输了比赛
I can't do that.
我做不到
Of course you can. After all, you've had plenty of practice.
你当然可以 而且，你很有经验
But the men. It's more important to them than it is to you.
但是你要知道 输赢对他们来说更重要
Okay. Suit yourself.
没关系，你自己选择
Spend the next 25 years of your useless life in prison.
就在监狱里继续碌碌无为的 待个25年怎么样
All right, I'll do it.
好吧，我同意
But I don't want my guys hurt. You get ahead, you coast. We clear?
但是不要伤害我的人 你们赢了就行了好吗?
Fine. Right after I get a two-touchdown lead.
没问题，我要领先两个 攻方持球触地分
I tell you what bothers me the most, warden.
我告诉你什么最困扰我 典狱长
That you're not gonna be out there on that field with us,
我担心你到了外边以后
getting what you got coming to you.
可能得不到你想要的
The only thing coming to me is victory.
胜利会属于我
Mean Machine.
邪恶战车
It's cute.
不错的名字
- Let's go, boy! - We can do it, baby!
-我们走吧 - 我们会赢的
Captain.
上尉
May I have a word?
你给我保证吗？
Don't worry, warden, we'll take care of business.
别担心，典狱长 我们会尽力的
I already have.
我已经稳操胜卷
What? We can win this on our own.
我们可以自己打赢的
Captain, a man in my position doesn't leave things to chance.
上尉，我不会听天由命的
Now, after you get a comfortable three-touchdown lead,
听着，等你领先3个触地得分后
I want you to inflict as much pain as humanly possible.
我希望你们继续猛打
Do not let up, you hear?
可别放松明白吗？
I want those cons to understand who owns them.
我要让这些囚犯知道谁说了算！
Do I make myself clear?
我说的清楚吗？
Oh, yes, sir.
是的先生！
Good.
很好
There's the kickoff, and we're under way in the second half.
下半场要开球了
Megget is finally brought down at the guards' 33,
麦吉特最终在对方33码处被断下
where Paul Crewe will take over.
保罗克鲁在这里接替他
And what a first half he's had.
以及上半时战果
Here we go! Here we go!
大家加油啊
Down, set!
进攻！就位
Y 45. Hut!
45码！
On first and 10, Crewe will pass.
克鲁过了第一个10码
- He's got Deacon wide open. - Come on.
他找到迪肯的空当
Oh, incomplete.
失败了
It's okay. Get your head up.
没关系，继续努力
It's all right, man.
没关系
Come on, Paulie.
来吧，泡利
Second and 10 from the 33. Crewe's looking for Deacon once again.
第二轮，克鲁依旧期待 从迪肯处进攻
- He's open!
他那又空当
But overthrows it. And it's picked off by Papajohn.
但是扔过了 被帕约翰接住了
Look out! He might go.
看着，他反攻了
Say goodbye.
说再见
Touchdown!
得分
The first mistake Crewe's made all day.
今天克鲁犯的第一个错误
Short memory, baby. We'll get it back. We'll get it back.
没关系的 我们会追回来
Defense, let's do this!
防御！
8:38 left in the third quarter,
上午8：38，第三次进攻
and Crewe has struggled thus far in the second half.
克鲁正在为后半时努力
The pitch to Megget. Oh, my! That ball is live!
把球扔给麦吉特 天啊，又失手了
It's picked up by Lambert.
被兰伯特捡到
He's at the 1 5, the 1 0, and he will score!
他在15码处，10码 得分在望
Yeah! T ouchdown! Yeah!
得分！！
Crewe took a shot on that play and he's getting up slowly.
克鲁摔倒了很慢的爬起来
Meanwhile, in the end zone, the guards have something to celebrate,
于此同时，狱警队在边场庆祝
as they find themselves up by two touchdowns.
庆祝他们连续两个 越过对方球门线的六分
This is simply a different Paul Crewe we're seeing here in the second half.
后半场的保罗克鲁 可真是发挥失常
There's the old Paul Crewe we love to write about.
保罗克鲁老矣 这么写吧
What the hell are you doing out there?
你在赛场上怎么回事？
I'm done.
我不行了
I'm out. That's it.
我完了，就是这样
- Where you hurting? - My knee.
- 你哪受伤了？ - 膝盖
- Seems okay to me. - Well, it ain't.
- 我觉得没事 - 是的
If Crewe can't go, I don't know how deep these guys are at quarterback.
如果保罗不上场 谁来做四分卫？
The guards will try to keep it away from Megget, so they'll pooch kick.
狱警队将尽力防卫麦吉特
Fair catch. Fair catch.
完美的接球
As Big Tony calls for the fair catch.
大东尼正为完美接球叫喊
Watch out. That was as late a hit as I've ever seen.
看看，这是有史以来最慢的撞击
And even some of the home crowd not liking that one.
而且人们看上去很不欣赏这个
Can of corn. Can of corn, and I'll be fine. Can of corn.
玉米罐，玉米罐 我没事的
Yeah, I'd have a hard time looking at me too.
我也不好过
Brucie.
布鲁西
Yeah, coach.
在这，教练
You're the only one that knows this offense, son. Now, do it.
这种进攻最适合你了，上吧
Coming into the game, replacing the injured Paul Crewe,
替换受伤的保罗克鲁的人是
is number 1, Brucie.
1号，布鲁西
All right, all right. Crewe's playing like shit.
好了来吧 克鲁打的太烂了
That's his problem. I'm gonna bring us back.
那时他自己的问题 我来了形势会好转的
Right, 32 Flex Dive Motion on one. Ready!
我们来个鹞子翻身
Break!
来吧
Yeah. It's Brucie's time to shine, baby.
现在是布鲁西时刻
Okay. Down, set. Hut!
来吧，进攻
There's the snap and the ball is fumbled. And the guards recover.
又一次失球 但是狱警们很快扑了上去
I knew I shouldn't have had that popcorn.
我不该吃那些爆米花
The guards are in command here as we move late into the third quarter.
现在狱警们在场上占主导地位
Ninety-eight. Hut! Hut!
来吧九十八
The give is to Potter. Back to Knauer.
球传给了鲍特 又回传给科纳瓦
He's got a man open deep downfield.
他在前场的到一个优势进攻位置
He'll throw the flea-flicker!
一个交替传球
And he's got it. Touchdown, guards.
接得很准，得分 狱警队
And this game is starting to look like a blowout.
看起来比分开始失控了
Hey, man, after all Caretaker did, this is how you show him love?
这就是你对 凯尔泰克的回报？
Don't worry about it.
别担心
You haven't changed one damn bit.
你一点也没变
All right. Down, set!
好了，来吧！
Back in at quarterback is Brucie,
布鲁西继续担任四分卫
who will try to find a handle on the ball this time.
看看这次会把球传给谁
Throw it, Brucie!
扔出去，布鲁西
Oh, shit!
真糟
And look out.
留神看
What a shot he took!
重重一击！
How much more blood do you want?
你还要我们损失多少？
I think the cons are just about out of options at quarterback.
我觉得囚犯队选错了四分卫
Hey, Skitchy, let me ask you something.
斯基奇 我有个问题要问你
When you popped the warden, was it worth it?
你打了典狱长，你觉得值吗？
Was it worth spending the rest of your life in here?
值得把你后半身都搭在监狱吗？
Was it worth it? It was worth every goddamn second.
当然值，每一秒都值得
What the hell is he doing?
他想怎么样？
Paul Crewe must be feeling better, because here he comes.
保罗克鲁应该感觉好多了 因为他又上场
All right, I missed you guys, so I'm back.
好了我想你们 所以我上场了
We got a lot of work to do. Let's get it going.
我想我们要做很多才能赶上
Deuce right, 89. Fly on two. Ready?
89码处来个袭击，行吗？
Break.
很好！
As we start the fourth quarter, cons down by three touchdowns.
第四轮进攻囚犯队已经落后 3个六分球
Black 90. Hut! Hut!
直捣90码！
Here comes the blitz, and no one's blocking!
又一个闪电战！
And Crewe will be sacked for a big loss.
克鲁被困在其中
That looked like a message to Crewe from his offensive line.
看上去又是克鲁进攻的信息
Did you see that, man? They're quitting on him.
你们看到了 有个空当
Okay, baby. Jailbreak Blitz. Ready?
来吧！还是闪电战术
We got that out of the way. I deserved it.
这是我应得的
- Now we gotta play some football. - Switch it! Switch it!
- 让他们知道什么是橄榄球 - 换位
Cons need to do something to get back in this game.
囚犯队得很努力才能 改变劣势
And that's not it!
可不是这样
And Crewe is leveled!
克鲁已经被瞄准
I don't think he's gonna get up from that one.
我觉得他可能爬不起来了
Nice hit!
不错的撞击
But he is. And I don't know how, after that last hit.
但是他还是爬了起来 真不知道他是怎么做到的
All right, punt team!
来次弃踢吧
Keep them off the field! We're going for it.
让他们比较远的地方开始 没问题吧
Dumbshits are going for it! Let's go! Let's go!
傻蛋菜会这么做 行动起来
Come on back, if he wants to get his ass kicked. Come on back.
回来吧，如果他想挨打
This is unbelievable.
简直太不可思议了
Fine. You guys don't wanna help me, I'll do it on my own. On two.
你们要是不想和我合作 我就自己来
Let's go, to the line.
去界限上
On fourth and 20,
在20码线上
the cons are gonna go for it. This could be the ball game right here.
囚犯队决定做一次努力 这才像是正式比赛
Red 98. Hut! Hut!
红队98注意
Crewe dodges the blitz, but he loses his helmet.
克鲁劈开了闪电战术 但是掉了他的头盔
And he's not going down.
他继续前进
He's got the first down.
不错的战果
Time-out!
暂停
- Man, oh, man. - Not bad.
- 这才是男人 - 不错啊
Huddle up.
集合
Look.
听着
I'm sure you already know this, but I never said it out loud.
我知道你们都猜到了 但是我还是要大声说出来
I did throw that game.
我放弃这次比赛了
I did it.
刚才是这样
I was in a bad way with some worse people.
我被坏人威胁
After I did it,
我这样做的时候
I felt so shitty I wish I would have just let them kill me instead.
我感觉糟透了 我觉得不如让人杀了我算了
Now the warden wants to pin Caretaker's murder on me
典狱长会要挟要我将 如果我不放弃这次比赛
if I don't throw this game.
他要将谋杀凯尔泰克 的罪责加于我
So it looks like I'm gonna get to know you guys a lot better,
看起来我们还可以相处更长时间
because I ain't doing that twice in a lifetime.
因为我不会两次犯同一错误
We got a little time left. We can still do this.
时间所剩不多 但是我们还可以挽回局面
I'm begging you. Put your hands in here.
我请求你们 把手放在这里
Okay. Thank you. Now, who are we?
谢谢你们 我们是谁？
Mean Machine!
邪恶战车
Come on, Mean Machine, let's go!
来吧！邪恶战车！
That's great news.
真是个好消息
All right. We got ourselves a game.
这次有赛的了
Brown 65. Hut!
棕色65
First and 10 from the 30. Crewe finds Deacon open in the flat.
第一次从10码到30码 克鲁找到迪肯德空当
The give is to Megget. And he fights his way for a 9-yard gain.
传球给麦吉特 他又使战线向前推进了9码
One yard, baby. One more yard.
一码，再来一码
Crewe tries a sneak. Or is it?
看克鲁在耍什么小把戏
He flips it back to Megget.
他把球传给麦吉特
Megget's got the first down and more.
麦吉特又在继续推进战线
And Megget is down to the 4-yard line, where it'll be first and goal.
麦吉特这次前进了4码 得分在望
Crewe hands it to Turley. And look at the big man go.
克鲁传球给特里 看这大家伙怎么做
T ackle him!
抱擒阻止他
Touchdown!
得分！
That was some rumbling, bumbling stumbling right there.
这里有不少兵乓声
And listen to the crowd
听听人群的欢呼吧
as this underdog con team is starting to win them over.
观众们也开始喜欢囚犯队
Third down and 6. Guards have the ball on their own 29-yard line.
现在狱警队在29码线上持球
Knauer needs a first down to put this game away.
科纳瓦需要一击获胜
White 50!
白队50
And look at Battle take off.
看看赛场上发生了什么
He knocks the ball loose!
他把球打飞了
There's a dogpile in the backfield. The refs are trying to sort it out.
这可真是成堆了 裁判员都有点糊涂了
My arm!
我的胳膊！
The cons recover!
囚犯队重夺进攻权
We got the ball! We got the ball! We got it! We got it!
我们抢到了球
With just over two minutes left to be played, this has turned into a game.
剩下的这两分多钟 好像才真正进入比赛
Crewe will start in great field position at the guards' 25.
克鲁在25码处开始新的进攻
And look at this formation. The guards, they're confused.
看场上的形势 狱警们好像很困惑
Shift over! Move!
快移过去
They're trying to call time-out, but there's the snap.
他们想叫暂停 但是来不及了
Moss is behind a wall of cons. I wouldn't wanna be in front of that thing.
莫斯被抛在人墙之后 我可不想被这样的墙撞上
And they'll score!
他们要得分了
- Hey! Is that legal? - Yeah, it is.
- 这样合法吗？ - 是的
- Is that a touchdown? - Yes, it is.
- 这样得分了？
What is going on here? Shit!
到底怎么回事？
And with the extra point, the cons are down by just seven.
加上额外的加分 囚犯队只落后7分
- Brucie! - Yeah. Yeah, coach.
- 布鲁西 - 在这呢，教练
I want you to go out there and kick off.
沃要你去中线开球
- I can do it. - Kick off!
- 没问题 - 开球
Brucie can't kick worth a shit.
他跟本就开不好
I know. Recover the ball.
我知道，去夺球
Jesus Christ, my savior. If you help me out with this one,
耶稣基督，我的救世主 如果你助我一臂之力
I promise to stop cheating on my wife with black guys. Amen.
我保证不再和那个黑人做 对不起我老婆的事了，阿门
Back in the game is Brucie, and he'll do the honors.
重返赛场的布鲁西 对这次机会格外珍惜
And it's a horrible kick.
开球开的太糟糕了
But the ball is tipped!
但是球还是跌撞着出去了
And the cons have come up with it!
而且囚犯队持球
- We got it! One time-out. - Got it. Got it.
真不错，来一次暂停
That's it, Brucie. Hey, hey! My bad. My bad. My bad. Come on.
这才是布鲁西 乖乖!
Give me that.
给我
Damn--
真见鬼
Well, that felt unnecessary.
没必要这样吧
Cons have enough time for one final drive.
囚犯队还有足够的时间 扭转局势
Crewe drops back to pass. He's under pressure.
克鲁在压力下后传
- Watch the pass! - He's looking for Deacon.
- 盯住 - 他在找迪肯
He gets the ball up, but he's leveled.
他接住了球 但是被防守队员擒抱
And Deacon's got it for a first down, but he stayed inbounds.
第一次进攻结束 还处在发边线球
Tick, tick, tick. The clock keeps running.
时间不挺的流逝
Clock's running. Clock's still running! Clock's still running!
还有时间！还有时间！
On the ball!
留心！
Goddamn it! Do something!
真见鬼！快做点什么！
Crewe. He's looking to throw. Under pressure again.
这次克鲁想要掷球了
Go! Get rid of it! Go! Go!
快！加油！
He pitches it to Megget. He's got some room.
他把球传给麦吉特 他还有机会
Here we go. Here we go. Go, Megg! Go, Megget!
麦吉加油！
- Go, Megget! - Get him!
加油！麦吉特
He could go all the way!
没人可以拦住他
But he won't!
但是……
Goddamn it!
真见鬼
And Megget is hit hard at the 4, and he's hurt.
麦吉特在4码处受到严重撞击 他受伤了
My knee, man!
我的膝盖，天啊
You busted your knee for us, we'll bust our ass for you.
我们需要你的膝盖 都指望你了
Hey, coach, I need a back!
教练，我们要个替补
Just win this shit.
一定要赢！
I'm going in.
我去
Coach, you serious?
真的吗？教练
Yeah, I'm serious.
当然
And look who's coming into the game.
看看谁上场了
You can do it!
你能做到
Get that old ass of yours in the end zone!
老家伙！你能笑到最后
We gotta win this thing! Come on!
我们会赢得比赛
No, no, no. Hey, old man.
等等，老头
Absolutely not. You're gonna get killed out here.
绝对不行 你会把自己的命赔到这
They've been trying that for years. Don't worry, I got the perfect play.
他们都跃跃欲试了 别担心,我会打好比赛
- I ain't handing you the ball. - You don't have to.
- 我不会把球给你的 - 看情况吧
Nate Scarborough, the former Heisman Trophy winner from 1955,
内特・斯卡波罗 1955年海斯曼奖杯获得者
is gonna play tailback,
上场打后卫
but he's gotta be in there more for moral support than anything.
不过他上场主要也只能提供 精神上的支持
Mean Machine. Mean Machine.
邪恶战车！邪恶战车
Six seconds left on the clock. Cons down by seven.
比赛还有6秒钟结束 比分落后7分
They must score on this play.
这一举必须得分
Don't let them through!
被让他们得逞！
Down, set!
进攻！就位
- Black 99! - Come on, D!
黑色99码！
The give is to the big man, Turley.
球给了大块头特里
He's stopped by Lambert at the line for no gain.
他被兰伯特拦截了
No! Wait!
太不可思议
The ball's picked up by Scarborough.
斯卡波罗捡到了球
Come on!
来吧
Touchdown!
得分
What an amazing comeback, folks!
真是精彩的一幕
Taking a play from the old Nebraska playbook.
这将载入内布拉斯加州的 比赛史册
The Fumblerooskie.
这一行动
Easy. Easy.
放松
You still alive, old man?
你还好吗？老头
Never felt better in my life.
这辈子感觉从没这么好过
You're a sick bastard. Come here.
你这个变态，起来吧
And now the cons are a mere extra point away from overtime.
现在囚犯队可以凭借额外的加分 不用进入加时赛
Mean Machine!
邪恶战车
Team vote: We go for the win? We go for the tie?
投票决定：我们继续打赢比赛 还是打个平手就够了？
Hell, guys, we're convicts. We always go for it all.
我们是罪犯 我们当然义无反顾
Unfortunately, that's why we're all in the joint.
不幸的是，这也是 为什么我们呆在监狱的原因
What would Caretaker do?
凯尔泰克会怎么样？
Give me that blackboard.
把那黑板给我
Yeah, come on!
来吧！
Are you serious?
你是认真的？
I don't know. That play is wack.
我不知道，这样打有点怪
It's gonna work.
绝对管用
It's gonna work. Let's go. On the ball.
会管用，来吧，上场
Let's go, y'all! Let's go!
来吧大家上场
I think it's gonna work.
我觉得没问题
And wait a minute. Crewe is coming back into the game.
几分钟的休息之后 克鲁回到赛场
The cons are gonna go for the win.
囚犯队会赢得比赛
They're going for it.
他们义无反顾
Crewe, trying to settle his team into formation.
克鲁在组织进攻
But there seems to be a lot of confusion.
但是看上去有点小问题
Come on! Run the play!
来吧，快开始
Turley! Turley. Over here.
特里，站在那边
Move your giant ass right here! Right here.
你站在这里，就这
Come on, baby. Come on.
来吧！宝贝！
The play clock is still running. Crewe better call a time-out.
比赛正在计时 克鲁最好叫下暂停
Come on, Crewe!
来吧，克鲁
They don't know what we're doing!
他们不知道我们在干什么
Run the play we set up.
就照我们计划的去做
I think you're still dizzy from that hit!
我觉得你刚才摔糊涂还没清醒！
The snap is to Deacon.
球快速传给迪肯
It's a trick.
是个骗局
He throws it to Crewe.
他扔给克鲁
They did it! Unbelievable!
难以置信，他们做到了
The cons win!
囚犯队赢了
We win!
我们赢了
Group hug in the shower tonight!
晚上洗澡的时候好好抱抱
Or not. Or not.
不用不用
Well, there you have it.
知道吗？
A bunch of ruthless criminals have beaten
一群残酷无情的罪犯 打败了
the men that uphold our justice system.
维护公正系统的国家机器
Criminals are people too, Chris.
罪犯也是人，克里斯
Now, give me your wallet.
现在！把钱包交出来
What?
什么？
Just kidding.
开个玩笑
You got a lot of balls, Crewe. You played a hell of a game.
你有更多机会得分的，克鲁 你打的真糟糕
And don't worry, I know you had nothing to do with Caretaker's murder.
而且别担心 我知道你和凯尔泰克谋杀无关
And I'll back that up.
我会支持你的
Thank you, baby.
谢谢你
Mean Machine! Mean Machine!
邪恶战车
You humiliated me. I can't believe you couldn't even win a fixed game.
你太让我丢脸了 你居然赢不了比赛
Now, where the hell does he think he's going?
他觉得自己要到哪去？
He's escaping.
他要逃跑
Officer, shoot that man!
警官，射杀那个人
But, sir, there's people.
先生，那有人群
Shoot him.
射杀他
Crewe!
克鲁
Captain, I order you to shoot that prisoner.
上尉 我命令你必须射那个罪犯
Shoot him! Fire!
射杀他！开火
Crewe!
克鲁！
Damn it, I'm giving you an order, captain!
我命令你，上尉
Pull the trigger!
块扣扳机
It's the game ball.
就是个球而已！
Hey.
嗨！
Why don't you stick this in your trophy case.
把这个做你的战利品收藏把
- You have a nice time, old man? - Yeah.
- 玩不错吧?老头 - 当然
Yeah? Okay. So, what do we do now?
下一步我们做什么？
Well, the first thing is, we tell the team where they're hiding Unger.
首先，我们要告诉大家 怎么狂扁昂格尔
Oh, I can't wait to see what Switowski does to him.
我等不及看斯韦托斯基怎么揍他了
Great game, sir.
真是不错的比赛，先生
That's a week in the hotbox!
去小黑屋呆一个礼拜吧
Who gives a shit?
谁TMD在乎啊?